Come down,
Lord.
Come down.
Come down,
Lord.
Come down.
All right, fam. Let's go ahead and turn
to Exodus the 20th chapter. We're going
to start with the reading
of the law.
Exodus
the 20th chapter. We're going to read
verses 1
through 17.
Exodus 20.
I'm going to read verses 1 down to verse
17.
When you get there, my brother, go ahead
and read.
all these words, saying, I am the Lord
thy God, which have brought thee out of
the land of Egypt, out of the house of
bondage. Thou shalt have no other gods
before me. Thou shall not make unto thee
any graven image, or any likeness of
anything that is in heaven above, or
that is in the earth beneath, or that is
in the water under the earth. Thou shalt
not bow down to them, nor serve them.
For I the Lord thy God am a jealous God,
visiting the iniquity of the fathers
upon the children, unto the third and
fourth generation of them that hate me,
and showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord would not
hold him guiltless that taketh his name
in vain. Remember the seventh day to
keep it holy. Six days shalt thou labor
and do all thy work, but the seventh day
is the Sabbath of the Lord thy God. In
it thou shalt not do any work, thou nor
thy son, nor thy daughter, thy man's
servant, nor thy maidervant, nor thy
cattle, nor thy stranger that is within
thy gates. For in six days the Lord made
heaven and earth, the sea, and all that
in them is, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and it honor thy father and thy
mother, that thy days may be long upon
the land which the Lord thy God giveth
thee. Thou shalt not kill, thou shalt
not commit adultery. Thou shalt not
steal. Thou shalt not bear false witness
against thy neighbor. Thou shalt not
coveret thy neighbor's house. Thou shalt
not coveret thy neighbor's wife, nor his
manervant, nor his maid servant, nor his
ox, nor his ass, nor anything that is
thy neighbors.
>> Amen. Let's go to Ecclesiastes, the 12th
chapter,
and we're going to read verses 13 and
14.
Ecclesiastes the 12th chapter
and we're going to read verses 13 down
to verse 14.
When you get there, my brother, go ahead
and read. Let us hear the conclusion of
the whole matter. Fear God and keep his
commandments for this is the whole duty
of man. For God shall bring every work
into judgement with every whether it be
good or whether it be evil.
>> All right, let's go to the last book of
the Bible.
Revelations 22
and we're going to read verses 14 down
to verse 15,
Revelations 22,
and we're going to read verses 14 and
15. When you get there, my brother, go
ahead and read.
Blessed are they that do his
commandments that they may have right to
the tree of life and may enter in
through the gates and to the city for
without are dogs and sorcerers and
whoreongers and murderers and idoltors
and whosoever love it and make a lie.
>> All right family that's the reading of
the law. We read it at the beginning. We
read it in the middle and we read it at
the end. That way there is no confusion
that you got to keep this law. The word
says this is the whole duty of man. So
if it's your whole duty of man to keep
the commandment, that's what you got to
do. Amen.
>> Happy Sabbath everybody.
>> Happy Sabbath.
>> My name is Brother DeAndre. I'm your
teacher from the Israel of God
Birmingham class. And read for me is
your very own brother Ray from the
Israel of God Bay Area class. I'm
excited to be here with y'all.
get the fellowship in the Bay Area. I
said, "I'm coming over to the West
Coast."
I said, "I couldn't wait to jump on that
plane. I almost didn't get no sleep."
But praise the Lord everybody that we
here on the Lord's Sabbath day. And
the title of today's lesson is, "Have
God cast away his people Israel?"
Have God cast away his people Israel?
Because You look at the world today
family
it would look like the other people
that's calling themselves Jews it seem
like they are the people of God
but through the scriptures
we have clearly identified who is the
children of Israel so now it come
to mind the question so if there's a
people that's walking around here
calling themselves Israel or from the
tribe of Jews when we know they are not
then it will seem like that the Lord
have replaced us with another people. So
it will look like the Lord have cast
away his people Israel and we talking
about the Israelites according to the
Bible. So we need to find this out. Have
God cast away his people? Because it's a
group of people that's walking around
talking about that they are us and we
know that they are not. So we got to
find Have God cast away his people
Israel? Let's dig into it. Let's go to
Jeremiah the 23rd chapter. Because the
thing about it, family, is that the
preachers have a responsibility
to teach the people who they are
and where they come from.
So every
should be feeding the sheep according to
the word of God, not what they think
that's on their mind or what happened
yesterday or anything like that. It
should be thus said the Lord because we
have a responsibility
to teach the people what God want
and the Lord going to deal with those
pastors that's not dealing true.
Jeremiah 23 we going to read verse one
down to verse 8 when you pick it up. Go
ahead and read.
>> Woe be unto the destroy and scatter the
sheep of my pasture.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Say the Lord. Therefore, thus say the
Lord God of Israel against the past that
feed my people. Ye have scattered my
flock and driven them away and have not
visited them.
>> Behold, I will visit upon you the evil
of your doings, sayeth the Lord.
>> Yes. And I will gather the remnant of my
flock out of all countries whether I
have driven them and will bring them
again to their foes and they shall be
fruitful and increase
>> and I will set up shepherds over them
that will which shall feed them and they
shall fear no more nor be dismayed
neither shall they be lacking says the
Lord.
>> Yes. So we have a respon the Lord is
against the pastors that are standing up
here and scattering the flock. The Lord
is going to visit those pastors. That's
why it baffles me how any person can
stand up here in this position and not
teach the true word of God. Obviously,
they haven't read Jeremiah 23. Maybe
they may read the verse to themselves,
but don't read it to y'all. Because when
they not read certain verse from y'all,
y'all would think that they teaching,
but thus said the Lord. But you got to
put the whole Bible on the table to find
out if your pastor is teaching you the
true word of God or not. That's why we
do that's why we have you to bring pen
and paper and your own book when you
when you up here with us because you can
read what we are reading to check us
out. We actually put ourselves on the
table to see if that way you can pull us
to the side afterwards. Hey pass on you
just said this and that. You just said
this. This not in here. We are letting
you guys in on examining us. Keep
reading, my brother.
>> Behold,
>> the days come, said the Lord, that I
will raise unto David a righteous
branch, and a king shall reign and
prosper, and shall execute judgment and
justice in the earth.
>> Uhhuh. We talking about Jesus here. Go
ahead.
>> In his days, Judah shall be saved, and
Israel shall dwell safely, and this is
his name, whereby he shall be called the
Lord our righteousness. Mhm.
>> Therefore, behold, the days come, said
the Lord, that they shall no more say,
the Lord liveth, which brought up the
children of Israel out of the land of
Egypt.
>> But the Lord liveth, which brought up,
and which led the seed of the house of
Israel out of the north country, and
from all countries whether I had driven
them, and they shall dwell in their own
land.
>> Oh, so this one people is going to know
who the Lord is for. when he have
gathered all of Israel out of the north
country and from all the countries that
he have driven them once he start
gathering his people Israel people going
to be like oh man this the Lord that
we've been reading about all this time
so this is how you going to know because
think about it family a lot of us
weren't back there when he took the
children of Israel out of Egypt was
nobody back there but in this time when
the Lord come and when he gather all his
Everybody going to know at that point
that's living. Go ahead. Where we at,
brother? That was verse eight.
>> Verse eight.
>> Skip down to verse 13. What does it say?
>> And I have seen folly in the prophets of
Samaria.
>> They prophesied in Bael and caused my
people Israel to
have seen also in the prophets of
Jerusalem and horrible things. They
commit adultery and walk in lies. They
strengthen also the hands of evildoers
that none return from his wickedness.
They are all of to me as Sodom and the
habit thereof as Gomorra.
>> One thing about it, when there is
wickedness going on, he look at all
wickedness the same. So if you are
serving a pagan god, he is looking at
you just like Sodom and Gomorra. It's
the exact same thing. Why? Because you
are committing adultery on your God. So
if you are committing adultery on your
God, he looking at you like, hey
God, you just like the
go ahead and read.
>> Therefore, thus said the Lord of hosts
>> concerning the prophets. Behold, I will
feed them with wood and make them to
drink the water of God.
For from the prophets of Jerusalem is
profane is gone forth into all the land.
Mhm.
>> Thus say the Lord of hosts, hearken not
unto the words of the prophets that
prophesy unto you. They make you vain.
>> Uhhuh.
>> They speak a vision of their own heart.
>> No, they speak of visions from the Lord.
>> Of their own heart.
>> From their own heart. How you know they
speaking from their own heart? Because
they standing up giving you two verses.
And then for two and a half, y'all ain't
even open up y'all book and turn to no
pages. Y'all just standing up there
looking at him. He just talking talking.
Everything that happened to him in his
life, it take him two and a half hours
to do that.
>> And you only read two verses. Everything
is coming from the imagination of his
own heart. Now, that's how you able to
check him out. Explore to a church. 30
minutes in, he give you two verses. 30
minutes after that, he still ain't gave
you no verses. You better grab your
quote and walk up out of there
>> because there's no point of being there.
Go ahead and read. They speak a vision
of their own heart and not out of the
mouth of the Lord.
>> They say still unto them that despise
me, the Lord have said,
>> Uhhuh.
>> Ye shall have peace.
>> And they say unto everyone that walketh
after the imagination of his own heart,
>> what they say,
>> no evil shall come upon you.
>> That's basically what they saying now.
You ain't got to keep THE WORD OF GOD NO
MORE. All you got to do IS CONFESS OUT
YOUR NAME, out your mouth, that Jesus
Christ is Lord, and then you're going to
be saved. And then the next day, you can
go out there and commit adultery,
fornication, and then come back to the
Lord and say, "I'm sorry, Lord." And
then what they what the pastor telling
you, "Ain't no evil going to come upon
you. You are saved now. You done called
upon the name of the Lord." And they
say, "No evil going to come upon you."
That is not from the Lord. Skip down to
verse 21. What does that say?
>> I have not sent these prophets, yet they
ring.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I have not spoken to them, yet they
prophesy.
>> Right? Because why he hasn't spoken to
them? because they haven't read you the
pages out of this book. The Lord say he
have not sent them. Go ahead and read.
>> But if they had stood in my counsel
>> and had caused my people to hear my
words, then they should have turned them
from their evil way and from the evil of
their doings.
>> Yes.
>> Am I a god at hand, said the Lord, and
not a god a far off?
>> Can any hide himself in secret places
that I shall not see him?
>> Right? It's like these is up here
teaching this false doctor act like the
Lord can't see them like the Lord don't
know what's going on in your mind. The
Lord got them angels looking dead at
everything that you doing and they
reporting back to the Lord. The Lord is
seeing everything. You think you going
to hide up under a rock and the Lord
can't find you. He is the master of hide
and seek.
>> HE IS GOING TO FIND YOU. SO when when
you think you up under that rock, the
Lord lift up that rock and said, "I got
you now." He always go find you. You
cannot hide from him. Go ahead and read.
>> Say the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Do not I feel heaven and earth?
>> Yeah. This a question. Go ahead.
>> I have heard what the prophet said that
prophesy lies in my name, saying, I have
dreamed. I have dreamed. How long shall
this be in the heart of the prophets
that prophesy lies? Yay, they are
prophets of the deceit of their own
heart.
>> Uhhuh. Since they are prophesying of
their own heart. But since they are
doing this, what does verse 27 say? Go
ahead and read.
>> Which think to cause my people to forget
my name by their dreams, which they tell
every man to his neighbor as their
fathers have forgotten my name for
>> they said they have forgotten. Think
about it. Don't nobody know who the Lord
is right now. Everybody is serving pagan
gods out here right now. But in verse 27
it says which think to cause my people
to forget my name. So now we need to see
what name are they causing the people to
forget. If in verse 27 it says which
thing to cause my people to forget my
name. We got to find out what that name
is that the people are causing them to
forget. Let's go to Psalms 83.
Let's go to Psalms
83.
We going to see what this
name is. Psalms 83. We're going to read
verses one down to verse three and then
we're going to skip down to verse five.
Let's find out what is the name they are
causing the people to forget.
Psalms 83. We're going to read verse one
down to three and then we're going to
skip to verse 5. Pick it up in verse
one, my brother. What does that say?
>> Keep not th Oh God. Hold not thy peace
and be not still, oh God.
>> For lo, thine enemies make a tumble and
They that hate thee have lifted up the
head.
>> Y
>> they have taken crafty counsel against
thy people and consulted against thy
hidden ones.
>> Skip down to verse five. What does that
say?
>> For they have consulted together with
one consent. They are confederate
against thee.
>> Okay. So all these people have took
crafty counsel against his people. Let's
see who they are. Verse six. the
tabernacles of Edom and the Ishelites of
Moab and the Hagarines Gibbal and Ammon
and Amc the Philistines with the
inhabitants of Ty.
>> Yes,
>> Ash is joined with them. They have hope
in the children of Lot
>> unto them as unto the Medidianites as
unto Ces.
>> Yes. as to yes at the brook of
>> read the book brother
>> which perished at indor they became as d
for the earth
>> make their nos like and like z yeah all
their princes as zeba and as zamuna
>> yes what verse 12 say
>> who said
>> what they say
>> let us take to ourselves the house of
god in possession
>> so all these nations of people said let
us take to our themselves the house of
God in their possession. But we read in
Jeremiah 23 that they have caused the
people to forget his name that they may
worship Ba. These all the ones that took
crafty counsel against our people. But
now we need to find out what is the name
are they causing the people to forget.
Skip up to verse four. What does that
say?
>> They have said, "Come and let us cut
them off from being a nation
>> that the name of Israel may be no more
in remembrance.
>> Oh, so we just found that after the name
of Israel that they causing the people
to forget. Think about it right now,
family. If you go up to somebody saying
that you Israelite right now, they gonna
think you the people from over there.
They don't know who you are, family. We
don't even know who we are. We think we
Africaname.
I was talking to somebody the other day.
It's like, no, we was there. We were
somewhere before we got there. People
don't even know that. They think we just
popped up in Africa. That because why?
All these nations of people have ceased
the name of Israel to be no more in
remembrance. That's why it's so hard for
us to break through the teaching to
today because ain't nobody teaching the
name Israel. Nobody is teaching it. So
if the name of Israel will be no more in
remembrance, then who did the Lord make
a covenant with? Then we need to find
this out. Let's go to Ezekiel 16.
I remember I was trying to spread spread
the word to somebody. He I I gave him a
fly. He looked at he baldled it up
thinking that we was thinking that we
was a part of the people that's over
there that's that's causing what's
happening over there. And it's like
trying to break through that to show
like brother we not them. All of us got
that hard time going on trying to we we
we already battling with the Sunday
Christian now. We also batting with the
other Hebrew Israelites. But now we
batting we battling with the news that's
being poured out today too because why
don't nobody know who the true Israelite
is today.
Nobody. We are battling with the whole
world family on this thing. It's like
soon as that come out your mouth they're
like hold on wait a minute. But it's
funny because it's all through the
Bible. But the pastors are not reading
this. Ezekiel 16, pick it up at verse
one. My brother, what does that say?
>> Again, the word of the Lord came unto
me, saying, "Son of man, cause Jerusalem
to know their abominations.
>> And say, thus said the Lord God into
Jerusalem, thy birth, and thy nativity
is of the land of Canaan."
>> Y
>> thy father was an Amorite, and thy
mother.
And as for thy nativity in the day thou
was born, thy nl was not cut.
>> Neither was thou washed in water to
supplee.
>> Thou was not salted at all, nor swaddled
at all.
>> Yes.
>> None I pied thee to do any of these
things unto thee, to have compassion
upon thee. But thou was cast out in the
open field to the lo of thy person in
the day that thou was born. Mhm.
>> And when I passed by thee, and saw thee
polluted in thine own blood,
>> Uhhuh.
>> I said unto thee, when thou was when
thou was in thy blood.
>> So when the Lord saw Israel in thy
blood, what does he say?
>> Live.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I said unto thee, when thou was in
thy blood, live.
>> Go ahead.
>> I have caused thee to multiply as the
blood of the field, and thou has
increased and waxing, and thou art come
to excellent ornaments. Thy breast are
fashioned, and thine inh.
>> Yes. Skip down to verse 9. What does
that say?
>> Then wash thee with water. Yeah. I
thoroughly washed away thy blood from
thee, and I anointed thee with oil.
>> Look at that. The Lord said he saw us
out there, and he sought to clean us up.
He said, "Nobody didn't have compassion
upon thee, but our Lord had compassion
upon us." Keep reading, my brother.
>> I clothe thee also with
and shed thee with badger skin.
>> So this is how you going to know who
Israel is. Keep going my brother.
>> And I ged thee about with fine linen and
I covered thee with silk.
>> What'd he do?
>> I decked thee also with ornaments and I
put bracelets upon thy hands and a chain
on thy neck.
>> No Israel wearing some chains.
>> THAT'S HOW YOU KNOW WHO HE IS.
Go look at the people that got chains on
their neck.
People want to always go to Deuteronomy
28 to show, well, you know, well, we was
the people that went into captivity. NO,
TAKE THEM TO EZEKIEL. I BET you the same
one that you teaching to, he got a chain
on his neck. That's how you know who he
is. Chains on our necks. Go ahead and
read, brother.
>> Y'all know I ain't lying. Now, some of
y'all took your took I saw somebody took
their chain in. Take it take it back
out. We know who you are.
Go ahead and read, brother.
>> And I put a jewel on thy forehead and
earrings in thine ears.
>> He did what? Put earrings in their ear.
Everybody got over here some earrings,
don't it? The women got them on. Don't
tuck them away. Women, don't try to take
them out now. And what else he do?
>> And a beautiful crown upon thine head.
>> He put a beautiful crown upon thy head.
What else he do?
>> Thus was thick with gold and silver.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And thy raignment was of fine linen and
silk embroidered work. Thou didest fine
flour and honey and oil and thou was
exceeding beautiful and thou disrossper
into a kingdom. Yes. So now we need to
see so if they are causing the people to
forget his name and we read in Psalms 83
that the name of Israel will be no more
in remembrance. And we already read the
nations who came against Israel. So we
need to find out who did the Lord make a
covenant with them. Skip back up to
verse eight. What does that say?
Now when I passed by thee and looked
upon thee, behold, thy time was the time
of love
>> and I spread my skirt over thee
>> and covered thy nakedness.
>> Yeah. I swear unto thee.
>> He swore unto us. Go ahead. And what he
do?
>> And entered into a covenant with thee.
>> Yes.
>> Say the Lord God. And thou became his
mine.
>> Also the Lord made a covenant with who?
Isel family. Israel is who he made the
covenant with. So if he made the
covenant with Israel, it don't matter
how many nations come against Israel,
they cannot break the covenant that the
Lord made with Israel. Cannot break the
covenant. So if the Lord entered into a
covenant with Israel and became his,
then let's make sure we understand that
the Lord entered into a covenant with
Israel. Let's make sure we understand
this. Let's go to Exodus 24.
Let's go to Exodus 24.
We all know we had we got chains on our
necks, baby.
Then we going to let it shine, too. You
know, we got to have the matching chains
with the bracelet and watch and the
earrings. That's how you know who we is.
We got to make it look good.
>> We got to make it look good before we
get out the store. We like, "Oh man, I
got the chain." You know, I got to get
the watch, too.
I know who he is.
Exodus 24,
we're going to read verses 1 down to
verse 8 because the Lord entered into a
covenant with Israel and we became his.
So let's make sure that we understand
that the Lord made a covenant with
Israel. Let's make sure we understand
this. Exodus 24,
we're going to read down to verse eight.
Let's make sure we understand this. Pick
it up at verse one, my brother. What
does that say?
>> And he said unto Moses, "Come up unto
the Lord, thou and Aaron, Nadab, and
Abu, and 70 of the elders of Israel, and
worship ye a far off."
>> And Moses alone shall come near the
Lord, but they shall not come, neither
shall the people go up with him.
>> And Moses came and told the all the
words of the Lord and all the judgments
and all the people answered with one
voice and said, "All the words which the
Lord have said we will will we do."
>> And Moses wrote all the words of the
Lord and rose up early in the morning
and builded an altar under the hill and
12 pillars according to the 12 tribes of
Israel.
>> Okay. So Moses wrote all the words of
the Lord. And what did Israel say? We
going to do them. We going to do them.
Go ahead and read.
>> And he sent young men of the children of
Israel, which offered burnt offerings
and sacrificed peace offerings of oxen
unto the Lord.
>> And Moses took half of the blood and put
it in basins. And half of the blood he
sprinkled on the altar.
>> Yes. And so we read in Ezekiel 16 that
the Lord entered into a covenant with
Israel, right? And we became his. Let's
take a look at how this covenant was
laid out. Go ahead and read. And he took
the book of the covenant.
>> Oh, so he took the book of the covenant.
Go ahead.
>> And read it and read in the audience of
the people.
>> Yes.
>> And they said, "All that the Lord have
said will we do."
>> Oh. So it was the book of the covenant
we got right now that Moses got. Go
ahead. What's in this book? Go ahead.
>> And be obedient. Andes took the blood
and sprinkled it on the people and said,
"Behold the blood of the covenant,
>> which the Lord hath made with you
concerning all these words."
>> Oh, so that's how the Lord entered into
a covenant with Israel. Moses took the
book of the covenant. And what he did?
He read all the words in the book of the
covenant. So that's how the Lord made a
covenant with Israel. When Moses took
the book, he sprinkled the blood on the
people and he read the words of the book
in the covenant. So now we need to find
out what are the words that is in the
covenant because it said behold the
blood of the covenant. So let's see what
this covenant is and what the book of
the covenant was that these words that
Moses was reading. We need to find this
out. Let's go to Exodus 34.
Exodus 34 because he read he took the
book of the covenant and he read the
words of the covenant. So now we need to
find out what was in those words
that Moses was reading to the people.
Exodus 34
and we're going to read one down to
verse 5.
Brother, you can untuck your chains.
Now, we we read that. We read past the
verse.
>> Take take it back out. All right.
Pick it up at verse one. What does it
say?
>> And the Lord said unto Moses,
>> Uhhuh.
the two tables of stone like unto the
first. And I will write upon these
tables the words that were in the first
tables which thou breakest.
>> Right? Because when Moses was getting
the words from the Lord on two tables of
stone, what we doing down there? We
partying and dancing. We took the golden
earrings out our ears and we done made a
golden cal and the feast with it with to
go with, you know, we wanted to do some
sin and put some dancing, some drinking
with it, too, right? That's who Israel
is. But the Lord said, "Hey, I need you
to two tables of stone like unto the
first." Moses, come back up here and get
this now. Just because you broke it
don't mean it's over with. Go ahead and
read
>> and be ready in the morning and come up
in the morning unto Mount Si
>> and present thyself there to me in the
top of the mount. And no man shall come
up with thee, neither let any man be
seen throughout all the mount. Neither
let the flocks nor herds feed before
that mount.
>> And he two tables of stone like unto the
first. And Moses rose up early in the
morning and went up unto Mount Si as the
Lord had commanded him and took in his
hand the two tables of stone.
>> Yes.
>> And the Lord descended in the cloud and
stood with him there and proclaimed the
name of the Lord.
>> Okay. So he got two tables of stone like
unto the first. And we read in Exodus 24
that Moses sprinkled the blood on the
people. And he read in the book of the
covenant the words. Right? So now we
need to find out what was the word that
Moses was reading out of the book of the
covenant. Skip over to verse 27. What
does that say? And the Lord said unto
Moses,
>> uh, "Write thou these words, for after
the tenor of these words, I have made a
covenant with thee and with Israel."
>> Didn't we just read this in Exodus 24
that he read in the audience concerning
these words, the book of the covenant.
So we read here in verse 27, he said,
"Write these words, for after the tenure
of these words have I made a covenant
with Israel." So what are the words?
Verse 28, what does that say? And he was
there with the Lord 40 days and 40
nights. He did neither eat bread nor
drink water. And he wrote upon the
tables the words of the covenant.
>> What are they?
>> The ten commandments.
>> Oh, so that's what Moses was reading in
the audience of the people. The ten
commandments. That's what we read in
Exodus 24. He said concerning these
words of the covenant, he was reading
the ten commandments. That's how the
Lord made a covenant with Israel family.
And we cannot break the covenant that
the Lord made with Israel after the
tenure of these words here. Can't nobody
break them. But what is the pastor
doing? Basically, the pastor is telling
you that the Lord has broke the covenant
that he made with Israel. So if he
didn't make the if he didn't break the
covenant that he made with Israel, that
means that the ten commandments still
stand. Family, we have to keep them. So
since the words of the covenant is the
ten commandments, then what did he
declare to Israel? What did he declare
to him? Let's find out. Let's go to
Deuteronomy the 4th chapter.
Deuteronomy the 4th chapter. It It's
funny when you when we get to talking to
people. I remember I was talking to this
one guy, you know, saying that the
commandments were done away with. I
started to reach into his pocket
I started reaching into his pocket. I
said, "Can I said, can you come in
close?" Started to reach into his, "Hey,
man. What you doing?" I said, "Man, you
said the the Ten Commandments done away
with, so I can go into your pocket and
steal your money." Oh, no. You can't do
that. But you just said the law's done
away with. Oh, but it's not done away
with when it comes to you though. That's
what it is. So, I can't reach into your
pocket and take the $100 bill that you
got in your wallet. I can't take it. So
because the law is still there and
people don't understand the covenant
that he made with Israel, they don't
even understand who Israel is.
Deuteronomy 4, we're going to read
verses 1 down to verse 13 because since
the words of the covenant is the ten
commandments, then we need to find out
what did he declare to the people. Pick
it up at verse one. What does that say?
Therefore hearken Israel unto the
statutes and unto the judgments which I
teach you for to do them that ye may
live and go in and possess the land
which the Lord God of your fathers
giveth you.
>> Yes,
>> ye shall not add unto the word which I
command you. Neither shall ye diminish
from it that ye may keep the
commandments of the Lord your God which
I command you.
>> That's why we cannot add to the words or
take away from it because the Lord is
the the one that gave us the words which
is the ten commandments. That's why we
can't add to the commandments and we
cannot take away from them. Why? Because
the Lord gave them to Israel. So we need
to stop trying to take away the Sabbath.
It seem like the rest of the world they
cool with everything else. Soon as you
get to the oh man way it was done away
with when he died on the cross. Don't
even understand what they talking about.
But go ahead and read.
>> Your eyes have seen what the Lord did
because of
>> all the men that follow
the Lord thy God have destroyed them
from among you.
>> But ye that did cleave unto the Lord
your God are alive, every one of you
this day.
>> Behold, I have taught you statutes and
judgments, even as the Lord my God
commanded me, that ye should do so in
the land whether you go to possess it.
therefore and do them. For this is your
wisdom and your understanding in the
sight of the nations which shall hear
all these statutes and say, "Surely this
great nation is a wise and understanding
people."
>> Wait a minute. So the commandments is
our wisdom and our understanding. So if
we do not have the commandments, that
means we do not have no wisdom and we do
not have no understanding. Do y'all
understand what we read here family?
There is no understanding without the
tenure of these words, family. There is
none. Go ahead and read.
>> But what nation is there so great who
have God so not unto them as the Lord
our God is in all things that we call
upon him for? And what nation is there
so great that have statutes and
judgments so righteous as all this law
which I set before you this day?
>> Go ahead.
Take heed to thyself and keep thy soul
diligently, lest thou forget the things
which thine eyes have seen, and lest
they depart from thy heart all the days
of thy life.
>> But teach them, thy sons and thy sons
sons.
>> Oh, wait a minute. So, not only are we
supposed to be eating these words, but
we are supposed to be teaching this to
our kids and our kids kids. This word
has to keep going for family. That's why
it's very important to let the Lord on
you raising your kids. Cuz trust me,
that butt whooping that you done gave
them is only going to stay for a little
bit. But when you teach them what thus
says the Lord, what he going to do to
them, WHEN THEY STOP FOLLOWING his word,
they know that that butt whooping they
can't get away from. That's why you got
to let the Lord in. Trust me, when you
let the Lord in, you going to have your
kids telling you, "I don't want the Lord
getting get mad at me, daddy. I don't
want the Lord getting mad at me, mommy."
It's like they took you all out the
picture. They ain't concerned about you
them making you mad. They concerned
about the Lord because that's what you
supposed to have their focus on. Family
had their focus on the Lord because by
way of you keeping their focus on the
Lord, they're going to be following your
words. Y'all see how that happens? Go
ahead and read especially the day that
thou stood before the Lord thy God in
>> when the Lord said unto me, "Gather me
the people together and I will make them
hear my words that they may learn to
fear me. are the days that they shall
live upon the earth, and that they may
teach their children.
>> The Lord going to keep telling us to
teach our kids. With thus said the Lord,
go ahead and read.
>> And ye came near and stood under the
mountain, and the mountain burned with
fire unto the midst of heaven with
darkness, clouds, and thick darkness.
And the Lord spake unto you out of the
midst of the fire. He heard the voice of
the words but saw no similitude. Only he
heard a voice.
>> That's why we are not supposed to have
no graven images of the Lord because we
only heard a voice. It's funny when I
saw somebody with a graven image on
their neck. I said, "Man, can you get a
graven image of the voice of the Lord?"
He said, "What you talking about,
brother?" "Well, I just read here that
we only heard the words of the Lord. So
get you a graven but just his words
then." I know what you talking about,
brother. Yeah, because you don't
understand the commandments of God.
That's why. Keep reading, my brother.
>> And he declared unto you his covenant.
>> Oh, okay. So, we read after 10 of those
words, he made a covenant with Israel,
right? And the ten commandments, let's
see what he declared. Go ahead.
>> Which he commanded you to perform.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Even ten commandments.
>> Yes.
>> And he wrote them upon two tables of
stone.
>> So, he declared his company that we got
TO DO WHAT? PERFORM
THEM. How do you perform them when you
are not committing adultery on your
spouse? When you are not committing
fornication on someone that you
encountered with. When you're not
stealing, you're not bearing false
witness. That's how you perform the
words of the covenant. Why? Because he
declared them unto us. It's killing me
how people say the law is done away
with, but then they can't tell me how
you supposed to perform, not commit
adultery if it's done away with. Don't
even make y'all see how simple this is.
It is so simple. So since the Lord
declared unto Israel his covenant even
ten commandments then we need to see who
has the Lord only known then since he
declared his covenant unto Israel. Let's
see who only has he known then. Let's go
to Amos
the third chapter
and we're going to read verses one
through two here.
Amos the third chapter
and we're going to read verses
one
through
I think the most sad part about it when
I run into somebody and they know they
supposed to keep his word, but then they
choose not to do them. At that point, I
just stopped talking to him at that
point. I said, "Look, man, you about to
dig yourself a big hole right now,
saying that, you know, you supposed to
follow his words and you not, I'mma do
you a favor and stop you from the words
coming out of your mouth, brother or
sister, because I'm telling you,
Sometimes we can hang ourselves as a
people with that spiritual rope and we
don't even know it because we don't got
no understanding. That's why it's
interesting when you give people the
word you see who got understanding or
not just by what come out of their mouth
and then what they doing? They just
regurgitating what they heard from their
pastor or what they heard from their
friends but they haven't actually read
it. Amos three. So since the Lord had
declared his covenant, even ten
commandments to Israel, then who has the
Lord only known? Then Amos 3, pick it up
at verse one. What does that say?
>> Hear this word that the Lord has spoken
against you, oh children of Israel,
against the whole family which I brought
up from the land of Egypt, saying,
>> what did he say?
>> You only have I known of all the
families of the earth. Therefore, I will
punish you for all your iniquities.
>> Also, the Lord has only what known
Israel family. That's why is that?
Because he we was the one that he made a
covenant with. That's why. So, since the
Lord has only known Israel out of all
the families of the earth, then let's
see if he had dealt with any other
nation besides the children of Israel.
Let's go to Psalms 147.
Let's find this out.
Let's see if he has dealt with any other
nation
since the Lord has only known Israel.
And he showed unto Israel his covenant,
even ten commandments. And he declared
his covenant unto us that we have to do
what? Perform
them. We have to perform the words of
the covenant. Psalms 147,
we're going to read verses 1 down to 12
and then we're going to skip down to
verse 18.
Let's find this out. Who has the Lord
only known then? Psalms 147.
Pick it up at verse
one. My brother, when you get there, go
ahead
and read.
>> Praise ye the Lord, for it is good to
sing praises unto our God.
>> For it is pleasant, and praise is
coming. The Lord does build up
Jerusalem. He gather together the
outcast of Israel. He health the broken
in heart and bindeth up their wounds. He
tell the number of the stars. He callth
them all by their names.
>> Wait a minute. The Lord call stars by
their name and we too busy trying to go
up there to get to the stars.
It's like we trying to go get the
understanding of the Lord. We will not
get there in his flesh and blood. So
just stay our butts on this earth and
stop trying to go over there to the moon
where the Lord told you that he's coming
right back here. Just stay put. Stop
trying to leave. But he said he called
all the stars by name. Why is this verse
five? Go ahead.
>> Great is our Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And of great power.
>> Yes.
>> His understanding is infinite.
>> We can't even understand the mind of the
Lord. We don't even know what's out
there. All we see is just what we look
and see. His understanding is infinite.
Go ahead.
>> The Lord lifted up the meek. He casted
the wicked down to the ground.
>> Yes. Sing unto the Lord with
thanksgiving. Sing praise upon the heart
unto our God.
>> Yes.
>> Who coverth the heaven with clouds, who
prepareth rain for the earth, who maketh
grass to grow upon the mountain. How can
you read this and doubt that a god don't
do exist? People want to ask, "How do
you know God exists? Did you just see it
rain the other day? Who did that?" Ain't
no book that you can find that no man
has done that. Ain't nobody going to
tell you that they have done that. But
we want to say that there's no God out
there who coverth the heaven with
clouds. Man ain't doing that. Go ahead
and read.
>> He giveth to the beast his food and to
the young ravens which cry.
>> He delightth not in the strength of the
horse. He taketh not pleasure in the
legs of a man. The Lord taketh pleasure
in them that fear him in those that hope
in his mercy.
>> Yes.
>> Praise the Lord, O Jerusalem. Praise thy
God, O Zion. Yes. Skip down to verse 18
because we need to find out if the Lord
has dealt with any other nation besides
Israel. Since we are the only families
of the earth that he have known. Skip
down to verse 18. What does that say? He
sendeth out his word and meltth them. He
causes his wind to blow and the waters
flow. He showed his word unto Jacob, his
statues, and his judgments unto Israel.
>> And we've been reading that in Exodus
34, Exodus 24, and Deuteronomy 4. So now
what verse 26 say?
>> He has not dealt so with any nation. And
as for his judgments, they have not
known them. Praise ye the Lord.
>> Oh, so the Lord has only been dealing
with Israel. And we are out of all the
families of the earth, he have only
known us. And we see here in verse that
he had not dealt with any other nation.
Why haven't he dealt with any other
nation? Because we was the ones that he
showed his covenant to family. That's
why. So the Lord showed his word unto
Jacob and the statues and judgments unto
Israel. Then who is supposed to give his
law then?
Let's find it out. Let's go to Romans
the 9th chapter.
Let's go to Romans the 9th chapter. All
we doing here at the Israel of God is
followers of God.
So now we need to find out since the
Lord showed his word to Jacob and his
statutes unto Israel. Then who is
supposed to give his law then? Who's
supposed to be giving it? Romans 9
and we're going to read verses
one down to verse five
because the Lord showed his statutes and
his judgment unto Israel. So then who's
supposed to give his law then? Who's
supposed to give it? Romans 9
and we're going to read verses one down
to verse five.
>> Pick it up at verse one, my brother.
What does that say?
>> I say the truth in Christ. I lie not. My
conscience also bearing me witness in
the Holy Ghost
>> that I have great heaviness and
continual sorrow in my heart. Yes, this
is Paul here. Go ahead.
>> For I could wish that that myself were
cursed from Christ for my brethren, my
kinsmen according to the flesh.
>> Uhhuh. Who are they?
>> Who are Israelites?
>> Yes.
>> To whom pertainth the adoption?
>> And the glory.
>> So they pertain the adoption and the
covenant. I mean, and the glory. Go
ahead.
>> And the covenant.
>> And the covenant of what else?
>> And the giving of the law.
>> Yes.
>> And the service of God and the promises.
>> Oh. So he show his statutes and his
judges unto Israel. And we just found
out that Israel is the one that's
supposed to be given the law. So if we
are supposed to be the ones giving the
law, then we have a greater
responsibility to make sure that we are
performing
the words that we are giving to the
people. Why? Because we are supposed to
be a wise and understanding people. We
can't be just be the ones giving the law
and we're not performing it because the
world is looking at us on how we
supposed to walk this walk family. And
we have to be an example of the people
who the Lord gave the word to. Go ahead
and read
>> who are the fathers and of whom as
concerning the flesh Christ came.
>> Y
>> who is over all God blessed forever.
Amen.
>> Yes. Since the Israelites pertain to the
adoption,
the covenants, and the giving of the
law, then what advantage does the Jew
have?
If we are supposed to be the ones given
the law, what advantage does the Jew
have? Let's find out. Let's back up to
Romans the third chapter,
and we're going to read verse one down.
Verse four, because
the Israelites pertain to the adoption,
the covenant, the glory, the giving of
the law. So what advantage does the Jew
have if we are the ones that pertain to
the adoption, the covenant, the glory,
and the giving of the law? What is that
advantage?
Romans 3,
pick it up at verse one, my brother.
What does that say? Advantage then hath
the Jew.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Or what profit is there of circumcision?
>> So what's the advantage then? Go ahead.
>> Much every way.
>> Why is that?
>> Chiefly because that unto them were
committed the oracles of God.
>> Oh, what are the oracles of God family?
It's the answers. So you got to come to
come to Israel to get the answers of God
family. We just reading the book here
because so if we have the answers from
God that means if we have the answers
that means that we supposed to be giving
the law to the people because we the
ones that have the answers.
So we are supposed to be performing this
word because we supposed to be giving
this word and because we have the
answers too. So we have a greater
responsibility than every other nation
out here under the sun. Everybody We got
it easy out here, family. We got to
perform this word and we got to teach
this word. Can't no other nation be like
that in the eyes of God unless they come
into the commonwealth of Israel. So now,
so since the Jew committed the oracles
of God, then to who sons did the Lord
raise up for prophets then if the Jew is
committed the oracles of God. So who Did
the Lord raise up a prophets? Then we
need to find this out. Let's go to Amos
the second chapter.
Three and four. Three and four. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Let's go three and
four. I didn't got to ahead of myself.
Now, I got excited. Let me get all three
and four because this is important right
here. This is real important. I got a
point to make here. Pick it up at at
verse Let's go back to um Romans 3,
third chapter. Pick it up at verse
three. We need this. Go ahead and read.
>> But what if some did not believe?
>> Uhhuh.
>> Shall their unbelief make the faith of
God without effect?
>> So what if some people don't even
believe that the Lord gave the oracles
of God to the Jew? What if the people
don't believe this? Does it make the
word of God of none effect? Go ahead.
>> God forbid.
>> God forbid. Just because you don't
believe that the Lord gave the word to
Israel doesn't mean it didn't happen.
>> You can believe it or not. We are
reading this book. And since we are
reading this book, everybody out here
can examine what the word has said. Just
because you believe it doesn't mean it
didn't happen or it's not happening
right now. Go ahead and read.
>> God forbid.
>> Yep.
>> Yeah. Let God be true
>> and every man a liar.
>> Yes.
>> As it is written that thou mightest be
justified in thy sins and mightest
overcome when thou art judged.
>> That's why you better watch out what you
say now. thinking that the Lord haven't
committed the oracles of God to Israel.
You better watch what you say because
just because come out your mouth that
you don't believe doesn't make the word
of God in none effect. You are a liar
and God is true. So we got to follow the
words of the Lord. So since the Lord
since the Jew committed the oracles or
oracles of God then let's see who did he
raise up for prophets then. Now let's go
to Amos the second chapter. Thank you
for that brother. We need
people don't even know who did the Lord
raise up for prophets then if the Jew
have the answers of God. Then who did he
raise up
for prophets?
Amos the 2 chapter
and we're going to read verse 10
through verse
12.
Since the Jew since it's the advantage
of the Jew committed the oracles of God
which is the answers then who did the
Lord raise up the prophets?
Amos two pick it up at verse 10. What
does that say, my brother?
>> Also, I brought you up from the land of
Egypt and led you 40 years through the
wilderness to possess the land of the
Amorites.
>> And I raised up of your sons for
prophets and of your young men for
Nazarites.
Is it not even thus, oh ye children of
Israel, said the Lord? Also, who did the
Lord raise up for prophets? The children
of Israel. Because the children of
Israel is who the God commanded the
oracles to. SO THAT'S WHY HE raised up
prophets among Israel. Why? Because they
have the answers. Go ahead and read.
>> But ye gave the Nazarites wine to drink
>> and commanded the prophets, saying,
"Prophesy not."
>> So since the Lord raised up prophets
from among the children of Israel, then
who did the Lord reveal his secrets to?
Then let's scoot right over to Amos the
third chapter. And we just want one
verse there. Verse seven.
So who did he reveal his secrets to?
Amos 3, pick it up at verse 7. What does
that say?
>> Surely the Lord God will do nothing. But
he revealed his secret unto his
servants, the prophets.
>> Oh, wait a minute. So the Lord revealed
his secrets to his prophets. And the
Lord raised up Israel for prophets. And
so we see here if he gave his secrets to
his prophets, why? Because Israel who he
committed the answers to. So if you want
to know the secrets and you want to know
the answers, then you got to come to
Israel. It's all that simple. The Jew
have the answers and the prophet has the
secrets. So if you want the secrets,
come to Israel to get the answers. Then
I hope this is making sense. So since
the Lord would do nothing but revealing
his secrets unto his prophets, then who
does the secret stop with then?
Let's find out. Let's go to Luke 16.
Let's go to Luke the 16th chapter and
we're going to read
one verse here,
verse
16.
If you want the answers
of God, then you have to come to Israel.
This is why the whole world is out of
course. If y'all can see here, family,
we have a big big responsibility because
guess what? The the go the gospel of God
got to be preached into the world and
then the end going to come. So who got
the job to do that to do that job? It's
us. Everybody in this room, the gospel
can't go forth if we're not in line with
God. Family, we have to be in line with
God to help carry out his mission. So
just showing up here on the Sabbath day
and going home is not enough for God. We
have a responsibility to go out in the
highways and the byways to show
everybody who the true God is. We have
to do our part. Luke 16. So now we need
to find out who does the prophet stop
within. If the Lord revealed to his to
his servants the prophets. If the Lord
raised up prophets among the children of
Israel. If the Jew committed the oracles
of God, then who do the prophets start
with? Luke 16, pick it up at verse 16.
What does that say?
>> The law and the prophets were unto John.
Since that time, the kingdom of God is
preached and every man presses into it.
>> That's why when you get to re
Revelations, who who y'all read from?
John.
So the law and the prophets were unto
John. That's why you got to read this
book from Genesis to Revelation because
you're going to read all about the
secrets of the Lord that's been revealed
to his prophets. And all we are doing
here in this position is telling y'all
what the prophets and what the apostles
have gotten. That's all we are doing. So
since the law and the prophets were unto
John, then let's see if the Lord have
cast away Israel. Since the prophets
Stop with John. Is Israel cast away?
Let's see. Let's go to Romans the 11th
chapter.
Let's go to Romans the 11th
I remember when I first came into this
word, you know, I was all happy and
excited and all this, but then I I
started to read. I said, "Oh, wait. I
got I got a bigger responsibility to do
than just show up here and just this
word and just go back home. No, no, no.
We got to show forth the Lord's glory.
But the most important thing is that we
got to let this word cleanse us, wash,
wash us so we can be a great
representation of God of what we're
showing to the people. We got to make
sure we are clean. That means that we
got to clean up ourselves way more than
anybody else got to clean up themselves
with. Because the same people that's
coming to you, they want to make sure
you because you got to show them how
they get they supposed to get clean.
It's way bigger than what we think.
Family, we have a greater
responsibility. And guess what? Since we
have a greater responsibility, we get a
greater butt whooping. We get a real
good butt whooping. Why? Because we are
the ones that's supposed to be carrying
this thing out. Romans 11, pick it up at
verse one. The law and the prophets stop
with John. Then let's see if the Lord
have cast away Israel. Then let's find
out. Romans 11, pick it up at verse one.
What does that say?
>> I say then, have God cast away his
people? God forbid.
>> Oh, we just found out the answer right
there. God forbid. Go ahead.
>> For I also am an Israelite of the seed
of Abraham of the tribe of Benjamin.
>> Paul letting you know that God have not
cast away his people, Israel. This is
what the title of today's lesson have
came up with. So we can close our books
and leave. Nope. I still got some more
scripture. So we about to break this
down to the ground from these verses
right here. Keep going. God has not cast
away his people which he forneew. Why ye
not what the scripture say of Elias? how
he make intercession to God against
Israel, saying, Lord, they have killed
thy prophets and dig down thine altars,
and I am left alone, and they seek my
life.
>> But what sayeth the answer of God unto
him?
>> Y
>> I have reserved to myself 7,000 men who
have not bowed the knee to the image of
Ba.
>> Look at that. The Lord has 7,000 men on
reserve. Why did he have them on
reserve, family? Because His word got to
come through. That's why he had THESE
PRO. NO MATTER HOW WE TRY TO MESS UP
GOD'S PLAN, the Lord always got
something on reserve. Why? Because his
word got to keep going through because
we are the ONES HE COMMITTED THE
COVENANTS WITH. So that's why he had
these men on reserve. Why? So his word
can get through generation through
generation through generation. That's
why we all here. So we need to be
thanking our God that he had these men
on reserve. But there are also another
out there as well too. Verse five, what
does that say?
>> Even so then at this present time also
there is a remedy according to the
grace.
>> So we talking about the present time NOW
WHAT HERE WE ARE THE REMNANT because I'm
be honest with y' my knee down the bay a
couple times when I was in the Christmas
tree. So I know I wasn't in that verse
four. I know I wasn't no reserve but I
know that I'm in that verse five though.
We are the remnant. You know if you that
rem you Man, I had them Christmas
presents, man. I like $12,000. I
definitely bow my knee to bail. But you
in that remedy, though. But the Lord had
to get through you. What? Those 7,000
men that was reserved, they didn't buy
this knee down to Bale. So now he can
push that word through to the remedy. So
you can find out, oh man, I'm not
supposed to be doing this. Oh, I'm not
supposed to be decorating no Christmas
tree. Oh, I'm not supposed to be eating
this pork. Oh, I'm not supposed to be
doing this. The Lord going to make sure
he get this thing through.
And we are here because of that family.
We are here because of that. So God has
not cast away his people. We need to
make sure we understand this because if
Paul is right in this, then he had to
get it from somewhere. Let's go back to
the law. Let's go to Isaiah 41.
He had to get it from somewhere.
So we need to find out
where
did he get it from?
I read that verse. I said the Lord has
some people on reserve that have never
bowed down.
So since they never bowed down, they
need to bail. That means that they know
who Baal was to teach his word to show
him this is not the one you supposed to
be following.
You see Bale, you see what he doing?
Let's line up and see if the image of
Bael coincide with thus said thus said
the Lord.
It doesn't.
That's why the Lord gonna make his word
plain for you to see what's out there
and we'll see what's in this book and to
see if it coincide with each other. And
then at that point, you got a decision
to make. Do I stay with the image of
Baal or do I come into the true
knowledge of God that the Lord has sent
somebody to me to show me his word? Now,
you got a decision to make. Do you go
against the world or do you go with the
Lord? But once you find out what the end
is, when you come into this thing, the
Lord got you at that point, he got you.
Because you know, as soon as you step
outside of his word, you know what? You
stepping right into that fire.
Stepping right into it. So since God has
not cast away his people, let's make
sure we understand this. Isaiah 41,
pick it up at verse one. My brother,
what does that say?
>> Keep silence before me, O islands, and
let the people renew their strength. Let
them come near. Then let them speak. Let
us come near together to judgement.
>> Who raised up the righteous man from the
east, called him to his foot, gave the
nations before him, and made him rule
over kings. He gave them as the dust to
his
>> sword and as driven stubble to his boat.
>> He pursued them and passed safely even
by the way that he had not gone with his
feet.
>> Yes.
>> Who hath wrought and done it, calling
the generations from the beginning.
>> Okay. Who did this? Go ahead.
>> I the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The first.
>> Yep.
>> And with the last.
>> Yeah.
>> I am he.
>> Oh, so we know this is Jesus here that
done this. Keep reading. The saw it and
feared. The ends of the earth were
afraid, drew near and came.
>> Skip down to verse eight because we read
in Romans 11 that God has not cast away
his people. Let's make sure we
understand this. Pick it up in verse
eight. What does that say?
>> But thou Israel are my servant,
>> Jacob whom I have chosen, the seed of
Abraham my friend.
>> Yeah. Thou whom I have taken from the
ends of the earth, and called thee from
the chief men thereof, and said unto
thee, Thou art my servant. Yes,
>> I have chosen thee,
>> and not cast thee away.
>> But look what the Lord said. He said, I
have chosen thee, I have not cast thee
away. So since the Lord has chosen Jacob
and has not cast them away, then we need
to look at the covenant of day and night
then because when you understand the
covenant of day and night, then you're
going to understand if the Lord have
cast away his people or not. So let's go
look at the covenant of day and night.
Let's go to Jeremiah 33,
>> verse 10.
>> Verse 10. I do got that in there. Go
ahead and read that, man. I mean, I'm
I'm trying to get to it, man. Let me
slow it down. That's why you got to have
a good reader with you.
>> Give me that verse 10. Keep me alive.
Please do. Go ahead.
>> Fear thou not for I am with thee. Be not
dismayed, for I am thy God.
>> Yes,
>> I will strengthen thee. Yeah, I will
help thee. Yeah, I will uphold thee with
the right hand of my righteousness.
>> Yes, because the Lord has not cast us
away. So now family. We're going to take
a look at the covenant of day and night.
The Lord gonna make this so clear that
you going to be able to go outside and
take a look at this. Y'all already did
when y'all came in here. So, let's go
take a look at it. Let's go to Jeremiah
33.
It's just something when it get good to
you just like a c a kid that had some
candy. You know when you get kids some
candy as soon as they eat they get to
dance and all that other stuff they get
to shake and stuff. That's how I feel.
When it tastes sweet to you, it tastes
sweet to you. Jeremiah 33
and we're going to read verse 19 down to
verse 26. So since the Lord has chosen
Jacob and not cast thee away. Then let's
take a look at the covenant of day and
night because the Lord has said
something here.
Pick it up at verse
19. My brother, when you get there, go
ahead and read.
>> And the word of the Lord came unto
Jeremiah, saying,
>> uhhuh.
>> Thus say the Lord.
>> Okay. So Jeremiah said the word had came
to him, right? Let's see what it say. Go
ahead.
>> If ye can break my covenant of the day
and my covenant of the night and that
there should not be day and night in
their season.
>> Okay. So if you can break the covenant
of day and night. Let's see what he
gonna say. Go ahead.
>> Then may also my covenant be broken with
David my servant
>> that he should not have a son to reign
upon his throne and with the Levites,
the priests, and my ministers.
>> Okay. So, if you can break the covenant
with day and night, that means he work
BREAK THE COVENANT WITH DAVID. CAN'T
NOBODY IN HERE BREAK the covenant with
day and night. You can't do it at all.
We can't even get close to the to the
sun. We getting burnt out right now up
on the ground. So try to come seven
inches off the ground. See if you don't
get burnt some more. You can't break the
covenant. Go ahead and read.
>> As the host of heaven cannot be
numbered.
>> Okay. As the host of heaven cannot be
numbered. Go ahead.
>> Neither the sand of the sea.
>> We can't measure the sand of the seed.
Go ahead. So will I multiply the seed of
David my servant and the Levites that
minister unto me.
>> Wait a minute. So you mean to tell me if
you cannot measure the heavens and
neither the saying of the sea then he's
going to multiply the seed of David. You
can't number the heaven and you can't
number the seed family. That means that
he is going to multiply the seed of
David. Ain't that so clear? So you mean
to tell me when I go put my feet in the
sand that I'm understand I can
understand his word and he going to
multiply the seed of David?
The Lord use everything around us to
make sure we understand his word so
plain.
>> So plain. Verse 23. What does that say?
The word of the Lord came to Jeremiah,
saying,
>> "Consider thou not what this people have
spoken, saying, the two families which
the Lord have chosen, he hath even cast
them off."
>> That's a question. Go ahead.
>> Thus they have despised my people that
they should be no more a nation before
them.
>> And we already read who those what those
nations was. Go ahead.
>> Thus said the Lord.
>> Now the Lord is saying here what he's
saying.
>> If my covenant be not day and night and
if I have not appointed the ordinances
of heaven and earth.
>> Okay, so if his covenant is not with day
and not with night and if he have not
appointed the ordinance of heaven said
said the Lord saying this, go ahead.
Verse 26,
>> then will I cast away the seed of Jacob
>> and David my servant so that I will not
take any of his seed to be rulers over
the seed of Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob.
For I will cause their captivity to
return and have mercy upon them.
>> Wait a minute. So if his covenant be not
with day and night, then he will cast
off the children of Israel. Then we
didn't we come in here and see the
covenant with day. And when the sun go
down, we going to see the covenant with
night. That means the Lord has not cast
away his people. Family. That's how
simple this is. It's too simple. So if
his covenant be not with day and night,
then we need to see what will happen
with Israel if this happens. Let's find
this out. Bag up to Jeremiah 31. So we
can go outside and see this plainly,
family. That's what I love about this
word. It's so plain that you can go see
it. So if his covenant be not with day
and his covenant be not with night, then
we need to see what would happen to the
children of Israel.
Jeremiah 31,
pick it up at verse 31.
When you get there, my brother, go ahead
and read. Behold the day the days come,
said the Lord, that I will make a new
covenant with the house of Israel and
with the house of Judah,
not according to the covenant that I
made with their fathers in the day that
I took them out, that I took them by the
hand to bring them out of the land of
Egypt,
>> which my covenant they break.
>> Yep.
>> Although I was in husband unto them,
said the Lord.
>> Yep.
But this shall be the covenant that I
will make with the house of Israel.
After those days, said the Lord, I will
put my law in their inward parts, and
write it in their hearts, and will be
their God, and they shall be my people.
And they shall teach no more every man
his neighbor, and every man his brother,
saying,
>> "Know the Lord, for they shall all know
me, from the least of them unto the
greatest of them, said the Lord. For I
will forgive their iniquity and I will
remember their sin no more.
>> That's why the Lord got them laws right
here in our mind to keep them right
here. We do not have to look down at no
fringes family. That's why I don't
understand why these verses not
understood. So if his covenant be not
with day and night, then let's see what
will happen to the seed of Israel. Pick
it up at verse 35. What does that say?
Thus said the Lord.
>> So the Lord is saying this. Go ahead.
>> Which giveth the sun for a light by day.
>> Don't we just see the the sun giving
light by day, right? We saw that coming
in here. Go ahead.
>> And the ordinances of the moon and of
the stars for a light by night.
>> Yes.
>> Which divideth the sea when the waves
thereof roar. The Lord of hosts is his
name.
>> Yes. So don't we see the moon and the
stars give light by night and the sun
give light by day? We see this right? We
can clearly see this. Go ahead and read.
>> If those ordinances depart from me from
before me, say the Lord.
>> So if these ordinances are nothing no
more, this is what the Lord saying. If
you do not see the sun give light by
day, and you don't see the moon and the
stars give light by night, if those
ordinances depart from the Lord, go
ahead and ring,
>> then the seed of Israel also shall cease
from being a nation before me forever.
>> Wait a minute, y'all. Kindly, so you
mean to tell me,
we can look outside right now to see if
Israel cast away or not? So you mean to
tell me that when the go down and the
moon and the stars give his life. We can
see if ISRAEL CAST AWAY OR NOT. AIN'T
THAT SO SIMPLE? It is so simple that we
can pull up the blinds.
>> And take a look outside
and see Israel not cast away. This is
simple, family.
It's simple. But I got some more I got
to get y'all cuz this is getting good.
We at verse 37, right?
>> Yes, sir.
>> Oh, let's get him some
salt around the rim. Verse 37, what does
that say?
>> Thus said the Lord.
>> Okay. Now, the Lord speaking again now.
He got to make this even more plain. Go
ahead and read.
>> If heaven above can be measured.
>> Okay. So, if you can measure the heaven,
go ahead.
>> And the foundations of the earth
searched out beneath. So if you can
search out the foundations of the earth
beneath, go ahead and read.
>> I will also cast off all the seed of
Israel for all that they have done, said
the Lord.
>> Oh my goodness. Wait a minute. Oh my
goodness. So you tell me. If I can't go
beneath the earth
to search that out, that means if I
can't go outside and measure the
heavens, if I can't do this, it means
that Israel is not That's the way your
measuring tape can't go that far,
family.
And you're not even up there to even
find out how long how long the HEAVEN IS
STRETCHED OUT. THAT MEANS IF you can't
do this, family, that means that Israel
is not cast away. This is simple. This
is so simple. That's verse 37, right?
>> Yes, sir. So, let's see what the Lord
said to Israel if they break his
covenant. Let's see what he said. Let's
go to Leviticus 26. Oh my goodness, that
just was so simple.
I love how the simplicity of it. And
guess what we going to do, family, when
we depart
and we get in our cars and we get to
mosey on down to our house, we get to
look up in the sky and say, "Well, Lord,
you ain't cast us away."
And guess what? The Lord said, "We got
to teach our sons and our sons." That
means our daughters, too. So when they
look up and they see that son, mommy,
daddy, the son is out, you get to say, I
know son and daughter, that means his
brother passed away. It is that simple.
Mommy and daddy, can you measure the
heavens? No, I can't. Son and daughter,
that means that Israel is not cast away.
Mommy, daddy, can you go search the
earth from beneath? No, I cannot. That
means Israel is not cast away.
So simple. Leviticus 26, pick it up at
verse one. What does that say?
>> Ye shall make you no idols, nor grave
image, neither rear you up a standing
image, neither shall ye set up any image
of stone in your land
>> to bow down unto it.
>> That means that Go ahead and read.
>> For I am the Lord your God.
>> Yeah, that means that your butt better
not be bowed bound to that big belly
Buddha.
You're not supposed to be bowed down
speaking something that you don't even
know you speaking because the Lord told
you plainly that you have not saw no
similar to only you heard a voice.
That's why you're not supposed to be
bound to no images. Go ahead and read.
Ye shall keep my
reverence my sanctuary.
>> I am the Lord. If you walk in my
statutes and keep my commandments and do
them, then I will give you rain in due
season, and the land shall yield her
increase, and the trees of the field
shall yield their fruit,
>> and your threshing shall reach unto the
vintage, and the vintage shall reach
into the sewing time, and ye shall eat
your bread to the full, and dwell in
your land safely.
>> Yes.
>> And I will give peace in the land, and
ye shall lie down. and none shall make
you afraid. And I will read evil beasts
out of the land, neither shall the sword
go through your land.
>> Wait a minute. So if you are keeping the
commandments of God, that means that the
Lord is protecting you from everything
that's going on around you. That means
that you walking through this world like
it's the matrix. Everything just flying
past you. You may bag, you may dug back
a little bit. You may see how far you
can bag back when you stuff now. But you
are nothing in this land is going to
come against you. That means the Lord
going to take all these evil things and
going keep them away from you. But you
got to keep his word. Why? Because after
the 10 of those words, the Lord made a
covenant with us. Go ahead and read.
>> And ye shall chase your enemies and they
shall fall before you by the sword.
>> Yes. Skip down to verse 14. What does
that say?
>> But if you will not hearken unto me and
will not do all these commandments.
>> Now you know the Lord always got to put
the good things, the benefits that come
with this word. But if you go away from
this word, that also got to be another
side that happens too. Go ahead and read
it. And if ye shall despise my statutes,
or if your soul abhore my judgments, so
that ye will not do all my commandments,
but that ye break my covenant.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I also will do this unto you, I will
even appoint over you terror,
consumption, and the burning
that shall consume the eyes and cause
sorrow of heart, and ye shall sow your
seed in vain, for your enemies shall eat
it.
>> Go ahead. I will set my face against
you.
>> So if you doing all this evil, the Lord
is going to set his face against you. Go
ahead.
>> And ye shall be slain before your
enemies.
>> They that hate you shall reign over you.
>> And ye shall flee when none pursue you.
>> Go ahead.
>> And if you will not yet, for all this
hearken unto me.
>> Look at this.
>> Then I will punish you seven times more
for your sins.
>> Oh, wait a minute. That's why we can't
get away from nothing. When we start
sinning against the Lord, you get hit in
the head with a pot.
You get hit in the waves with a bat and
then the German shepherd gonna bite you
on the foot all at the same time. We
can't get away from nothing. But all
other nations, they may get hit in the
head with a plastic pot. But why the
Lord tearing us up though? Because we s
against him. Why? Because the Lord gave
his word to us. So we are supposed to be
conducting ourselves on another level
because if we are conducting ourselves
on another level, guess what? The Lord
going to bring them punishments unto us
on another level, too. So we have a
That's why we got to walk this word out.
Go ahead and read.
>> And I will break the pride of your
power.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And I will make your heaven as iron and
your earth as brass.
>> Yep.
>> And your strength shall be spent in
vain. For your land shall not yield her
increase, neither shall the trees of the
land yield their fruit.
>> Wait a minute. Since you are not doing
what you are supposed to be doing, the
Lord is going to punish you seven times
more and then he going to do something
to the land too. He said it's going to
yield her increase. Why? Because you're
not following his word. Go ahead and
read. And if you walk contrary unto me
>> and will not hearken unto me,
>> I will bring seven times more plagues
upon you according to your sins.
>> He said he going to bring seven times
more. That's why when you go to jail,
they going to hit you with a ticket and
then probably put an ankle mon.
The Lord is going to get you, Israel.
That's why when you come in this word,
you got to stay in it. That's why
everybody in here should have a in their
mind. Even if I slip away a little bit,
that's when the Lord is going to give me
seven times more. You may slip away from
the Lord. Next thing you know, the Lord
took away your job. You can't provide
for your family and you homeless.
That's what the Lord can do to you if
you step away from his word. Oh, Israel.
Why? Because he punish
him because he can take everything from
us that gave to us just like that. Go
ahead and read.
>> I will also send wild beasts among you,
>> which shall rob you of your children
>> and destroy your cattle and make you few
in number and your highways shall be
destined.
>> Yep. Go ahead.
>> And if you will not be reformed by me by
these things, but will walk contrary
unto me.
>> The Lord said, "If you walk contrary to
me, guess what I'mma do to you?" Go
ahead.
>> Then will I also walk contary unto you.
>> So wait a minute. So the Lord is going
to walk contrary to us and then what he
going to do? Go ahead.
>> And will punish you yet seven times for
your sins.
>> Wait a minute. So while the Lord is
hiding his face from us and he walking
contrary to us, he going to leave them s
right when he right when we left. So as
soon as you leave him, that moment you
leave him, he's out of your sight. And
he going to punish you seven times more.
And then notice it. When people fall
away from this thing and they get
punished seven times more, they know the
Lord gave them a rep. They can't even
come back to the Lord no more. That's
why you better pay attention to yourself
and make sure you have your house in
order because this thing is serious. Go
ahead and read.
>> And I will bring the sword upon you.
>> Y
>> that shall avenge the quarrel of my
covenant. And when ye are gathered
together within your cities.
>> Okay. So when you are gathered gathered
together, you know, having a good time
and all that and you forgot about the
Lord and all that, let's see what he do.
Go ahead.
>> I will send the pestilence among you
>> and ye shall be delivered into the hand
of the enemy.
>> So while you think you having a good
time, Israel, I'mma send pestilence
right upon you. And we already seen one
of those pestilence that came while we
was out there having a good time
partying and not thinking about the
Lord. He said he going to send them to
you Israel. Skip down to verse 27. What
does that say?
>> And if you will not for all this hearken
unto me.
>> Okay. So all this I didn't I didn't all
these plagues upon you. You done walk
contrary to me. I don't walk contrary to
you. And if you still don't come back,
go ahead and read.
>> But walk contrary to me. Uh-huh.
>> Then I will walk contrary unto you also
in fear.
>> Wait a minute. I'm going to be mad. I'm
going to be mad when I'm walking away
from you. And since I'm so mad that I'm
walking away from you, Israel, what I'm
going to do to you?
>> And I even I will chastise you seven
times for your sins.
>> So not only have I turned my faith from
you, I'm also mad while I'm turning my
face from you. And then I'mma punish you
seven times more. That's why we should
have no reason why mad against any other
nation of people. This is our God doing
this to us. So if y'all walk around with
this hate in our heart with these other
nations of people, you need to look at
your God because your God doing this to
you. Your God is doing this to you. And
in all this, understand if we would had
just by reading the book, we would
understand that the Lord is punishing us
and that other nations, they just got a
hand. They just they just a part of the
play. They just a part of the why
because we fell away from our God. What
verse we at?
>> We at 29.
>> We at 29. Go ahead and read it.
>> And you shall eat the flesh of your sons
>> and the flesh of your daughters shall ye
eat.
>> And this happened family. This he said
when you walk contrary to me, I'mma make
you eat kids. And if this is written
family, this happened. Why? Because we
already read that we already contrary to
the Lord. And guess what? We were
sacrificing our kids to Moab and we was
too. When the Lord put that whammy on
you, family, you cannot get away from it
unless you turn back to your God. Go
ahead and read. And I will destroy your
high places and cut down your images and
cast your carcasses upon the carcasses
of your idols, and my soul shall abhore
you.
>> Yes. And I will make your cities waste
and bring your sanctuaries unto
desolation. And I will not smell the
savior of your sweet odors.
>> And I will bring the land into
desolation, and your enemies which dwell
therein shall be astonished at it.
>> Yep.
>> And I will scatter you among the
heathen, and will draw out a sword after
you, and your land shall be desolate,
and your cities waste.
>> Wait a minute. So the Lord had walked
contrary to us.
seven more time scenes on us. And when
he had scattered us, guess what? He put
a swore right to us at the same time. So
now he done walk contrary to us. And
then he done scattered us. So now we
getting scattered. He put that sword and
cut you off by an all Israel. He cut you
off. And now you don't even know what's
going on. Why? Because you s against
your God. So now you trying to flee from
your enemies that the Lord have driven
you to. He gonna cut you right there
seven more times. Skip down to verse 36.
What does that say?
>> And upon them that are left alive of
you, I will send a faintness into their
hearts in the lands of their enemies.
>> Wait a minute. So the ones that are left
alive among you, I'mma get them, too.
I'm not letting
pass since you chose to walk contrary to
me. I'mma come after the one that I left
alive. Go ahead. And the sound of a
shaken leaf shall chase them, and they
shall flee as fleeing from a sword,
>> and they shall fall when none pursue it.
>> And they shall fall one upon another as
it were before a sword when none pursue
it. And ye shall have no power to stand
before your enemies.
>> You ain't gonna have no You ain't gonna
have no say so. Why? Because you fell
from me. Ain't nobody listening to you
and don't nobody care about you since
you fell away from you. I didn't even
walked away from you. So now guess what?
We are left alone out here. Go ahead and
read. And ye shall perish among the
heathen and the land of your enemies
shall eat you up.
>> And they that are left of you shall pine
away in their iniquity in your enemies
land.
>> Y
>> and also in the iniquities of their
fathers shall they pine away with them.
>> Yeah. So all this we fell away from the
Lord and the Lord have walked contrary
to us run seven more times on us and
then not only did he walk away from us
he walked away from us in furious he was
so mad but there's always something else
on the table for us to get back to our
God once we have realized what we have
done. This is the merciful side of him.
Keep reading my brother.
shall confess their iniquity and the
iniquity of their fathers with their
trespass which they trespassed against
me and that also they have walked
contrary unto me.
>> Y'all see this here? It says if they
confess. So you got to confess your
iniquity. But then you also have a
responsibility to to confess the
iniquities of your ancestors too.
You got to put them in your equation too
because they are the reason why we are
here.
So you got to confess not only your sins
but their sins as well too. Go ahead and
read.
>> And that I also have walked contrary
unto them
>> and have brought them into the land of
their enemies. If then their
uncircumcised hearts be humbled and they
then accept of the punishment of their
iniquity.
>> Uhhuh. If you accept the punishment that
the Lord is putting on you right now
with you confessing your sins and the
sins of your fathers, go ahead and read.
Then will I remember my covenant with
Jacob and also my covenant with Isaac
and also my covenant with Abraham will I
remember and I will remember the land.
>> Uhhuh.
>> The land also shall be left of them and
shall enjoy her Sabbaths while she lie
desolate without them. And they shall
accept of the punishment of their
iniquity because even because they
despise my judgments and because their
soul abhored my statute.
>> Go ahead and read.
>> And yet for all that when they be in the
land of their enemies.
>> So all this when you be in the land of
your enemies. Go ahead and read.
>> I will not cast them away. Neither will
I abort them to destroy them utterly and
to break my covenant with them. for I am
the Lord your God.
>> So when you confess your sins and the
iniquities of your fathers, then he
going to remember the covenant that he
made with Abraham, Isaac, and Jacob. And
then while you are scattered in the land
of your enemies, the Lord is letting you
know, I will still not cast you away.
I'm still not going to cast you away.
Why? Because I made a covenant with you.
And because you broke your covenant with
me doesn't I'm going to break my
covenant with you.
That's the merciful side of the Lord. He
is a covenant God. He is standing there
waiting on us to get our acts together.
And as soon as we get our act together,
he's going to remember the covenant that
he made with our fathers. Go ahead and
read, brother.
>> But I will for their sakes remember the
covenant of their ancestors.
>> Uhhuh. So since you prayed for the
iniquities of you and your
Then he said he's going to remember the
company that he made with your
ancestors. It's not just about us right
now in this generation family. We are
doing this for them.
That's why we have a bigger
responsibility because we are supposed
to be doing what they couldn't do.
That's why we have a huge responsibility
to get our stuff together, get our act
right, get our our houses in order, make
our and our sons know what thus say the
Lord because we are doing for their sake
and our sakes. Go ahead and read
>> whom I brought forth out of the land of
Egypt in the sight of the heathen that I
might be their God.
>> Yes,
>> I am the Lord.
>> Yes. So since the Lord will remember the
covenant he made with Jacob, Isaac, and
Abraham, then who will be his people
when he come back?
Let's see this to investigate this.
Who's going to be his people when he
come back? So now we got to go to the
future. Let's go to Ezekiel 36.
Let's go to Ezekiel 36.
We got to take a look at the future.
Now,
Ezekiel 36,
we're going to read verse 22
to 23.
Then we're going to skip down to verse
25. I pray this this lesson is making
sense, family. I pray it is making
sense.
The thing about the Lord When you read
this, as soon as you slip away, do some
stuff you supposed to be doing, you
already know what's going to come. You
already know what's going to come. But
then at that point, you just got to
pray, "Hey Lord, just don't cut me off
too bad. Just just just slice me a
little bit so I can just put a band-aid
on my arm.
Just like just because it's going
and the thing about the Lord is that we
don't even know when he gonna get us."
That's why. So if you don't know when he
going to get you, that's why you got to
stay in his word and don't fall away
from him. You don't know if he get you
there or he may wait a little bit. He
may be wait to get you like I should get
him. Let me make sure get act together.
We don't know how he going to do us. And
since we don't know, that's the thing
where it's like we got to stay on the
right course. Ezekiel 36, pick it up at
verse 22. My brother, what does that
say?
>> Therefore, say unto the house of Israel,
thus say the Lord God, I do not this for
your sakes, oh house of Israel,
>> but for my holy name's sake,
>> which ye have profained among the
heathen, whether ye will win.
>> Yeah. He said, I'm not doing this for
you. I'm doing this for me. Why? Because
I'm the one that made the covenant. Even
though you broke it, I'm doing this for
me because I'm remembering my words that
I confessed unto you. Even though take
heed to the words that I confessed unto
you, I'm still going. Let's go ahead and
read.
>> And I will sanctify my great name.
>> Yeah.
>> Which was profained among the heathen,
which ye have profained in the midst of
them. And the heathen shall know that I
am the Lord, sayeth the Lord God, when I
shall be ified in you before their eyes.
>> Skip down to verse 25. What does that
say?
>> Then will I sprinkle clean water upon
you
>> and ye shall be clean from all your
filthiness and from all your idols will
I cleanse you.
>> The Lord is going to cleanse us and you
don't have to go to bath and body works
to get this type of cleansers.
No Irish spring.
Duh. None of that s lotion that you
women like to use. Trust me, I already
know you like you got some on. I smelt
it.
>> I smelt it. It hit my nose. But from
here, the Lord is going to cleanse you
up. This is the everlasting Irish spring
here. He going to clean you up from all
the filthiness, from all the idols. And
then what he going to do once he cleaned
us up, wash us up. He got under our
arms.
Even shaved the hair up on us, too.
Let's see what else he done did. Go
ahead.
>> A new heart also will I give you.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And a new spirit will I put within you.
>> And then what he going to take away? Go
ahead.
>> And I will take away the stony heart out
of your flesh.
>> Yeah.
>> And I will give you an heart of flesh.
>> Yeah. So he going to cleans us up.
>> And then what? He going to put his word
in our minds. Why? Because he made a
covenant with Israel. So he had to clean
us up first. Give us his word and then
comes a new heart too because our hearts
forgot to be circumcised to the Lord as
well too. Go ahead and read.
>> And I will put my spirit within you. Y
>> and cause you to walk in my statutes and
ye shall keep my judgments and do them.
>> Wait a minute. So how can his judgment
and and his statutes be done away with
if when he come back he going to teach
us those same statutes and judgments
that we keep trying to throw away? He
will come back in the future and give
those same judgments to do them. But
skip up to verse 24. What does that say?
>> Yeah, let's do that. Yeah. 28:29. I'm
sorry. That's what I'm talking about,
man.
>> I keep trying to cut it, don't I? Go
ahead and read 28:29.
>> And ye shall dwell in the land that I
gave to your father.
>> Yeah.
>> And ye shall be my people, and I will be
your God.
>> Yeah. because he's going to gather us
and take us right back to the land. But
he got to take us to the ruin first now
to make sure he purs all that stuff that
we ain't taking that over in the land
because he is not letting no foolishness
over there to the land. So he got to
clean us up first when he take us over
there to that wilderness. Then at that
time he's clean us giving us a new heart
and a new spirit. Now that our minds is
right now we can go straight into the
land. But he going to purge you and kill
you if your mind ain't right in that
wilderness when he gather us. Go ahead
and read.
>> I will also save you from all your
uncleanliness.
>> Yep.
>> And I will call for the corn and will
increase it
>> and lay no famine upon you.
>> Yep. Now skip up to verse 24. What does
that say?
>> For I will take you from among the
heathen.
>> He going to take us from among the
heathen. Go ahead.
>> And gather you out of all countries and
will bring you into your own land.
>> Okay. So at this time he comes back,
he's going to gather us and then take us
into our own land. But now
reading this, he said, "I will take you
from among the heathen and gather you
out of the countries and will bring you
into your own land." So now we need to
find out will the Lord only be gathering
Israel or will he have other nations of
people where he gathering also? Let's
see if he have Anybody else out? Let's
see. Let's go to Isaiah 56.
Let's go to Isaiah 56
because we see that the Lord will gather
Israel and bring them into their own
land. Let's see if he have others that
he's going to gather also
when he makes his gathering. Isaiah 56,
we're going to read verses one down to
verse 8.
Because the Lord is going to gather
Israel and bring them into their own
land. Let's see if he will gather others
to him also.
Let's find this out. Isaiah 56, pick it
up at verse one. My brother, when you
get there, go ahead and read.
>> Thus say the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
Keep ye judgement and do justice, for my
salvation is near to come, and my
righteousness to be revealed.
>> Blessed is the man that doeth this, and
the son of man that lay hold on it, that
keepeth the Sabbath from polluting it,
and keepeth his hand from doing any
evil.
>> Yes. He said, "Blessed is the man that
doeth him." He's talking about the man.
We ain't talking about just Israel. Go
ahead and read. Neither let the son of
the stranger that have joined himself to
the Lord speaking.
>> So neither let the stranger say this. Go
ahead and read.
>> The Lord have utterly separated me from
his people. Neither let the unic say
behold I am a dry tree.
>> The unic and the stranger cannot say
that the Lord has utterly separated them
from his people. You won't be able to
say that. Why? Go ahead and read. For
said the Lord, unto the unics that keep
my Sabbath.
>> Okay, we talking about the Unix keeping
the Sabbath. Go ahead.
>> And choose the things that please me and
take hold of my covenant.
>> Yes.
>> Even unto them will I give in my in my
house and within my walls a place and a
name better than of sons and of
daughters. I will give them an
everlasting name that shall not be cut
off.
>> Wait a minute. The Lord said he would
give them an everlasting name that they
shall not be cut off. He is talking
about the strangers and the unics here.
So they cannot say that the Lord has
utterly separated them from his people.
No, no, no. We are all in this together
as one body. Go ahead and read.
>> Also the sons of the strangers that join
themselves to the Lord
>> to serve him and to love the name of the
Lord to be his servants. Everyone that
keepeth the Sabbath from polluting it
and taketh hold of my covenant.
>> Wait a minute. So not only does Israel
got to keep the Sabbath, but the
strangers and the unit got to keep it,
too.
We are all supposed to be on one accord
serving the same God. Everybody, the
whole world, don't matter which son or
daughter that came out of Noah.
Don't matter. Go ahead and read.
>> Even them will I bring to my holy
mountain and make them joyful in my
house of prayer. Their burnt offerings
and their sacrifices shall be accepted
upon mine altar.
>> Uhhuh. For my house shall be called in
house of prayer for all people. Oh, so
this house going to be what? Call a
house OF PRAYER FOR ALL PEOPLE. The Lord
is not leaving nobody out. Yes, the Lord
has not cast away Israel, but the Lord
also not casting away the strangers and
the unics either. Also, we are all his
house be called a house prayer for all
people. Keep reading verse eight because
we read in Ezekiel that the Lord will
bring Israel to their own land whether
he have scattered them he going to
gather others to him also verse eight
what does that say
>> the Lord God which gatherth the outcast
of Israel said
>> and we read that already in Ezekiel
right go ahead and read
>> yet will I gather others to him beside
those that are gathered unto him
>> oh wait so the Lord not only going to
gather Israel but he got the nations of
people that he going to gather to
himself also. The Lord is not leaving
nobody out. Why? Because the house of
the Lord is be going to be called the
house of prayer for all people. That's
why he is gathering everybody else
outside of Israel family. But now we
need to see why will the Lord gather
others to him also besides Israel. Why
is he going to do this? Let's let the
book talk. Let's go to John 10.
Let's go to John the 10th chapter
because the Lord is not leaving nobody
out. The stranger cannot say that he has
utterly separated me from his people.
Can't say that at all. We are all
brothers and sisters in this walk. No
matter what color nationality your
father is, it does not matter. You want
the If you want to serve the Lord, take
hold to the covenant that the Lord made
with Israel. That's all that simple. All
All it is is a protocol. That's all it
is. And shoot, when you when you find
out that you is a part of Israel, when
you from their nationality, you like,
man,
I see I see the B a lot more harder than
the other nations.
It's a lot more harder. a lot more
harder.
John 10, we're going to read verse one
down to verse 16 because we need to see
why
will the Lord gather others to him also.
Why is he doing this? And this is Jesus
talking right here. John 10, pick it up
at verse one. What does that say?
Veryily, verily, I say unto you, he that
enterth not by the door into the
sheepfold, but climbth up some other
way, the same is a thief and a robber.
>> But he that enterth in by the door is
the shepherd of the sheep.
>> Yes.
>> To him the porter openth, and the sheep
hear his voice, and he calleth his own
sheep by name, and leadth them out.
>> Yes.
>> And when he put forth his own sheep, he
goeth before them, and the him for they
know his voice.
>> Uhhuh. We talking about the sheep that's
following the Lord's voice. Go ahead.
>> And a stranger will they not follow but
will flee from him for they know not the
voice of strangers.
>> Yep. Go ahead.
>> This parable spake Jesus unto them. But
they understood not what things they
were which he spake unto them.
>> Yes. They didn't even understand what
Jesus was talking about. So now Jesus
like let me break down this to you
plainly so you can know what I am
talking about. Read verse seven. What
does that say?
>> Then said Jesus unto them again verily
verily I say unto you I am the door of
the sheep.
>> Y
>> all that ever came before me are thieves
and robbers but the sheep did not hear
them.
>> I am the door. Y
>> by me if any man enter in, he shall be
saved
>> and shall go in and out and find
pasture.
>> Yeah. So he said if any man
that excludes just Israel family, he
said if any man enter in by me, he shall
find pasture. Go ahead and read.
>> The thief cometh not but for to steal
and to kill and to destroy. I am come
that they might might have life and that
they might have it more abundantly.
>> Yes,
>> I am the good shepherd. The good
shepherd giveth his life for the sheep.
>> Yes.
>> But he that is entirely and not the
shepherd whose own the sheep are not
seeth the wolf coming and leaveth the
sheep and fle and the wolf catches them
and scatters the sheep.
>> Go ahead.
>> The hirling fle
is in hling and cares not for the sheep.
Think about it, family. These preachers
out here that's preaching tomorrow do
not care about you. I remember I was at
the grocery store. I was evangelizing.
I'm giving up some cars and stuff. Ran
into a deacon. I'm like, "Oh, okay." I
already got my church and all that. I'm
like, "Okay, cool." I said, "So, do you
guys keep the Sabbath?" He said, "No,
no, no. We go to church on Sunday." I
said, "Why?" I said, "Let me read to you
what Jesus said." He said, "No, no, no.
you. I'm pretty sure you already know,
you know, know more than me, but I'm
just telling you just by traditions,
that's what we do.
>> Man, I wish I would had my phone to
record that. I said, "Wait a minute." I
told I said, "Brother, so you mean to
tell me that you know that we are
supposed to be keeping Lord Sabbath day,
but you just told me out your mouth that
you doing it because of traditions? You
are killing your people." He hurried up
and slammed that door in the car.
These preachers know, but because of
traditions or because they think that
the people won't show up on on the
Sabbath, they don't want to change over.
They do not care about the sheep.
Because if you change and you tell your
congregation that what you've been
teaching is wrong, you got to have a
humble spirit to do that. But they
rather not be humble and keep filling up
their pockets in order to not look wrong
in the eyes of the people.
>> Shouldn't be doing that. Go ahead and
read, brother.
>> I am the good shepherd and know my
sheep.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And am known of mine.
>> Yep.
>> As the father knoweth me.
>> As the father know of him. Go ahead.
>> Even so know I the father.
>> Yes.
>> And I laid down my life for the sheep.
>> Say he laid down his life for the sheep.
And remember we read in Isaiah 56 that
the Lord will gather the outcast of
Israel. And he got others that he going
to gather to him also. Let's see. Why is
that? Verse 16. What does that say?
>> And the other sheep I have which are not
of this fold.
>> Oh, that's why he going to gather others
to him all also because he has other
sheep that is not of this fold. What
fold is he talking about? The children
of Israel. That's the fold. So he got
other sheep that's not a part of the
fold of Israel. And guess what? The Lord
laid down his life for them. So if he
laid down his life for them, then we
shouldn't prevent them to come to hear
what thus say the Lord because they are
included in them this also. Finish that
up, brother.
>> Them also I must bring.
>> Yes.
>> And they shall hear my voice.
>> He said they also that I must bring.
That mean that is a definite that this
is going to happen. He's going to bring
them. Go ahead and read.
>> And there shall be one fold and one
shepherd.
>> And there's going to be one fold and one
shepherd. Why? Because it's because
house is going to be called a house of
prayer for all people. So let's take a
look at the other sheep that's not a
part of this fold. Let's take a look at
them. Let's go to Ephesians the second
chapter. He got other sheep that is not
of this fold.
And it's so crazy that
the other Hebrew brothers out there
don't even understand these scriptures
and they don't understand that they are
the modern day Pharisees which trying to
keep the Lord from the people. But here
at the Israel of God, we're not doing
that. We're going to stick with the book
and if the book says it, then we have a
obligation to read it. We have an
obligation to line upon line,
precept upon precept. You can't read in
there and talking about that it said the
world. We're just talking about Israel.
If he said it's the world, he talking
about that he that he took on the sins
of the whole world.
He ain't just talking about just Israel.
Ephesians 2, we're going to read verse
10 down to verse 14 because we're going
to take a look at these other sheep
that's not of the fold is Ephesians 2,
pick it up at verse 10. What does that
say?
>> For we are his workmanship.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Created in Christ Jesus unto good works.
>> Yes.
>> Which God has before ordained that we
should walk in them. Mhm.
>> Wherefore remember that ye being in time
past Gentiles in the flesh,
>> Yes.
>> who are called uncircumcision, by that
which is called the circumcision, in the
flesh made by hand.
>> Go ahead.
>> That at that time ye were without
Christ, being aliens from the
commonwealth of Israel,
>> and strangers from the covenants of
promise, having no hope, and without God
in the world.
>> Yes. because the Lord was only dealing
with Israel. And so he said that at that
time you were without Christ being
aliens to the commonwealth of Israel at
that time. But now let's see what time
we are in now. Keep reading, brother.
>> But now in Christ Jesus, ye who
sometimes were far off are made not by
the blood of Christ. Also when Christ
laid down his blood,
everybody have access to eternal life.
Everybody go ahead and read what verse
14 say.
>> For he is our peace.
>> He is our peace.
>> Whoath made both one.
>> So he is our peace and he made both one.
Go ahead.
>> And hath broken down the middle wall of
partition between us.
>> Oh, so there's no more middle wall
between us and the rest of the sons and
daughters of Adam. There is no more a
middle wall. Christ took down that
middle wall. So since there is no more
middle wall, that's why we are all one
body, family. We are all one body. Skip
down to verse 18. What does that say?
For through him we both have access by
one spirit unto the father.
>> Yes. Now therefore you are no more
strangers and foreigners but fellow
citizens with the saints and of the
household of God.
>> Yes. They said we are no more strangers
and foreigners. Why? Because the Lord
has taken down the middle wall in
between us and the rest of the sons and
daughters of Adam. There is no more
middle wall. We are all one body serving
the God of Israel. Go ahead and read.
and are built upon the foundation of the
apostles and prophets. Jesus Christ
himself being the chief cornerstone.
>> Yes, that's why you need the prophets
and the apostles because why? Those are
built with Jesus Christ being the chief
cornerstone. What is that saying? You
can't have the prophets without the
apostles and you can't have the apostles
without the prophets. You need both of
them because then you going to
understand who the chief cornerstone is.
So since the Gentiles are no more
strangers and foreigners, but our fellow
citizens with the saints,
then we need to see if we are made both.
One, let's see if he will hear the
prayers of the strangers. Because what
do we do when we close out? We all face
Jerusalem, right? Let's see if the Lord
will hear the prayers of the strangers
when we close out. Jerusalem. Let's take
a look at it. Let's go to First Kings
8th chapter
because there's no more middle wall
between us, right? So, if there's no
more middle wall between us, then we
need to see if the Lord will hear their
prayers or not. Then,
first Kings the 8th chapter,
we're going to read verse one down to
verse two
and then we're going to skip down to
verse 9. There is No more no more a
middle wall between us.
The only middle wall there is that is is
that we going to get our butt whoop
seven times more and they won't.
That's that's it. And I'm pretty sure
that we're teaching the rest of the sons
and daughters of Avenue that we going to
get our butt whooped seven times. We
should be teaching them that they
shouldn't get their butt whooped at all.
None at all. First Kings 8, we're going
to read verse one down to verse two.
Because since the Gentiles are no more
strangers and foreigners, but our fellow
citizens with the household of the
saints and took down the middle wall
between us, then let's see if he would
hear the prayers of the strangers. And
then we also need to find out the
biblical definition of what a stranger
is. Pick it up at verse one. What does
that say? Then assembled the elders of
Israel
>> and all the heads of the tribes, the
chiefs of the fathers of the children of
Israel.
>> And to King Solomon in Jerusalem, that
they might bring up the ark of the
covenant of the Lord out of the city of
David, which is Zion.
>> Yes.
>> And all the men of Israel assembled
themselves unto King Solomon at the
feast in the month Ethan. Yes. Which is
the seventh month.
>> Yes. Skip down to verse n. What does
that say?
There was nothing in the ark save the
two tables of stone which Moses put
there at
>> Hel when the Lord made a covenant with
the children of Israel.
>> And we already been reading that which
is the ten commandments that was written
on two tables of stone. Go ahead.
>> When they came out of the land of Egypt.
>> Yes. Skip down to verse 20. What does
that say?
And the Lord has performed his word that
he spake.
And I am risen up in the room of David
my father
>> and sit on the throne of Israel as the
Lord promised and have built an house
for the name of the Lord God of Israel.
>> Yeah. So Solomon has built his house,
right? Let's see what he said after this
verse 21. What does that say? And I have
set a place for the ark
>> wherein is the covenant of the Lord.
>> Y
>> which he made with our fathers when he
brought them out of the land of Egypt.
>> Yes.
>> And Solomon stood before the altar of
the Lord in the presence of all the
congregation of Israel
>> and spread forth his hands toward
heaven.
>> Yep. And he said, "Lord God of Israel,
there is no God like thee in heaven
above or on earth beneath who keep his
covenant and mercy with thy servants
that walk before thee with all their
heart." So Solomon is he has built the
house for the Lord. Now Solomon is at
this point praying to the Lord. Let's
see what's all included in this prayer.
Skip down to verse 27.
and continue to read.
>> But will God indeed dwell on the earth?
>> Behold the heaven and heaven of heavens
cannot contain thee. How much less this
house that I have bu the heaven of
heavens can't even contain contain you.
Now I'm about to build this house is
made of wood and stone for you.
That that is the sincerity that Solomon
is saying. Basically is like man what I
have done it don't compare to you Lord
it doesn't at all because the heavens of
heavens cannot contain you what's more
of this house that is the humbleness of
what Solomon is saying to the Lord keep
going yet have thy respect unto the
prayer of thy servant
>> and to his supplication oh Lord my God
to hearken unto the cry and to the
prayer which thy servant pray before
thee
Yeah. So Solomon about to make this
prayer. What does that include? Go
ahead.
>> That thine eyes may be open toward this
house night and day, even toward the
place of which thou has said.
>> My name shall be there, that thou mayest
hearken unto the prayer which thy
servant shall make toward this place.
>> And hearken thou to the supplication of
thy servant, and of thy people Israel,
when they shall pray toward this place.
and hear thou in heaven thy dwelling
place and when thou hearest forgive.
>> Yeah. So he said when Israel pray
towards this house I need you to hear
their prayers that you may hear their
prayers and forgive them. That was verse
30.
>> Skip down to verse 35. What does that
say?
>> When heaven is shut up and there is no
rain because they have sinned against
it. If they pray toward this place and
confess thy name, and turn from their
sin when thou afflictest them, then hear
thou in heaven, and forgive the sin of
thy servants,
>> and of thy people Israel, that thou
teach them the good way wherein they
should walk,
>> and give rain upon thy land, which thou
has given to thy people for an
inheritance.
>> Yeah. So, he is making this petition.
He's talking about to Israel.
if they pray towards this house, hear
their prayers and forgive their sins.
But now we read in Ephesians the second
chapter that the Lord has taken down the
the middle wall between us that that the
Gentiles are no more strangers from the
commonwealth of Israel. Right? Let's see
if he will hear their prayers. Then skip
down to verse 39. What does that say?
here thou in heaven thy dwelling place
and forgive and do and give to every man
according to his ways whose heart thou
knowest for thou even thou only knowest
the hearts of all the children of men.
>> Yes. Go ahead.
>> That they may fear thee all the days
that they live in the land which thou
gavest unto our fathers.
>> Yes. Now let's see. So Solomon has made
this petition to the Lord. Lord, I need
you when Israel is towards this house,
hear their prayers, and forgive their
sins.
Let's see if he have included anybody
else in their prayer. In that prayer,
this is Solomon we talking about.
Continue to read.
>> Moreover, concerning a stranger.
>> Okay, so Simon is talking about the
strangers. What is the biblical
definition of a stranger? Go ahead.
>> That is not of thy people Israel.
>> That is the biblical definition. The
strangers is not with the people of
Israel. Go ahead and read.
>> But cometh out of a far country for thy
name sake.
>> We'll go ahead.
>> For they shall hear of thy great name
and of thy strong hand and of thy
stretch th when when he shall come and
pray toward this house.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Hear thou in heaven thy dwelling place
and do according to all that the
stranger to thee for that all the people
of the earth may know thy name to fear
thee as do thy people Israel.
that they may know that this house which
I have built is called by thy name. Wait
a minute. So Solomon have included the
strangers in the prayers. Why is that?
Because there's no more middle wall
of partition between us and the
strangers. So since there's no more
middle wall, Solomon already understood
what the future was looking like. So if
they if Israel pray towards this house,
I need you to hear them prayers. And I
also need you to hear the prayers of the
strangers. Why? Because we are both one.
And his house shall be called a house of
prayer for all people. So since Solomon
has made this prayer for Israel and for
the strangers, we need to find out if
God even heard this prayer at all from
heaven. Let's go to First Kings 9. Pick
it up in verse one. What
And it came to pass when Solomon had
finished the building of the house of
the Lord and the king's house and all
Solomon's desire which he was pleased to
do that the Lord appeared to Solomon the
second time as he had appeared unto him
at Gibon.
>> Okay. So the Lord appeared unto him a
second time.
Solomon has made this prayer for Israel
and the strangers. Let's see if he heard
it. Go ahead and read. And the Lord said
unto him,
>> what did he say?
>> I have heard thy prayer and thy
supplication that thou has made before
me, I have hollowed this house which
thou has built to put my name there
forever, and mine eyes and mine heart
shall be there perpetually. Wait a
minute. So the so the Lord heard the
prayer of Solomon that he included with
the strangers and with Israel. The Lord
heard this. Why? Because there is no
moment wall between us. Why? Because the
Lord has other sheep that's not of this
fold Israel. Why? Because the Lord will
gather Israel and he have others that
he's going to gather to him also. So the
Lord is going to hear their prayers.
Why? Because we have both have we have
access by one spirit even to the father
with Jesus Christ being the chief
cornerstone. We all are one body. So now
let's see where will the Lord dwell at
in the future if his eyes said if
Solomon said that his eyes will be there
perpetually. This came from the for the
Lord. His eyes will be there
perpetually. Well, let's see where he's
going to dwell at when he comes back in
the future. Let's go to Psalms 132.
Let's go to Psalms
132. The Lord is going to hear all their
prayers. Why? because they are now part
of the common of Israel. There is no
more middle wall between us.
There is no more middle wall between us.
Psalms 132. So we see Solomon made a
prayer for Israel and the strangers and
the Lord said that he his eyes is there
perpetually
towards the house that some has built.
So let's see where he would dwell at the
future. Then Psalms 132, we're going to
read verse 11 down to verse 14.
When you get there, my brother,
go ahead and read.
>> The Lord has sworn in truth unto David.
>> Uhhuh.
>> He will not turn from it. Of the fruit
of thy body will I set upon thy throne.
>> Yep. My children will keep my covenant
and my testimony that I shall teach
them. Their children shall also sit upon
thy throne forever more.
>> Yes.
>> For the Lord has chosen Zion.
>> He hath desired it for his habitation.
>> Then he say his eyes will be there
perpetually.
Go ahead and read verse 14.
>> This is my rest forever.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Here will I dwell.
>> Yes.
>> For I have desired it.
>> Why? Because that's where his eyes are
at. So if his eyes are there perpetually
and he's going to dwell here, that is
the place where he's going to dwell and
that's going to be his place of
habitation forever. So since the Lord
has chosen Zion for his habitation
forever, then who will the Lord reign
over then? If he has chosen Zion to
dwell at for his habitation forever, who
he going to reign at while he is there?
Let's let the book talk. Let's go to
Luke the first chapter.
Luke
And I got two more places after this.
Can I make it? Can I make it?
>> All I can make it. All right. And I just
saw it don't get dark here till about
9:30.
So I actually got enough time to do this
lesson again. Start over and do it
again.
>> We got enough time, family.
Luke 1, we're going to read verse 30
down to verse 33. Because since the Lord
has chosen Zion for his habitation
forever, then we need to see who will
the Lord reign over. And we saw that
Solomon made a prayer for Israel and the
strangers. And the Lord said his eyes
will be there perpetually, which is
Jerusalem, which is Zion. So who will he
reign over while he is there since
that's his habitation for ever? Luke 1
and we're going to read verse 30 down to
verse 33.
Pick it up at verse 30. My brother, when
you get there, hold on. Hold on. Still
here a few pages.
The sun is still out. That means Israel
is not cast away.
>> And we already read that this is the
ordinance forever. And you can't go up
there and measure the heavens either.
You can't So put your tape measure and
put it in your pocket. Don't stretch out
that far. Luke one, pick it up at verse
30. What does that say?
>> And the angel said unto her, "Fear not,
Mary, for thou has found favor with God.
And behold, thou shalt conceive in thy
womb and bring forth a son, and shall
call his name Jesus."
>> Yes,
>> he shall be great, and shall be called
the son of the highest. And the Lord God
shall give unto him the throne of his
father David.
>> And we read that in Psalms 132, right?
Go ahead and read.
>> And he shall reign over the house of
Jacob forever. And of his kingdom there
shall be no end.
>> So wait a minute. So Solomon
prayed for the people in Israel and we
read that the Lord eyes will be
perpetually towards Jerusalem. And we
also read in Psalms 132 that the Lord
has chosen Zion. This is where his rest
is at and this is where he's going to
dwell forever. So since he's going to
dwell there forever, we read in Luke 1
that the Lord is going to reign over the
house of Jacob forever. Remember he said
he's going to gather Israel and take
them into his own land, right? And he's
going to gather other to him also. And
that's where he's going to reign at over
the house of Jacob forever.
So Jesus shall reign over the house of
Jacob, and have broken down the middle
wall between us and the strangers. Then
where shall all nations keep the feast
of tabernacles in the future when the
Lord comes into Jerusalem? Let's see
where is the feast going to be at when
he comes back, which is his rest
forever, which is Jerusalem. Let's go to
Zechariah the 14th chapter.
Zechariah 14th chapter and we're going
to read verse 16 to verse 19 and then we
got one more place after this. There is
no more middle wall between us
family. No more middle wall. Now since
the Lord has chosen Zion and that is his
habitation and his rest forever and he
going to reign house of Jacob there.
Let's see where all nations have to come
to keep the feast of cha tabernacles
when the Lord comes and dwell in his
habitation.
Zechariah the 14th chapter and we're
going to read verse 16 to verse 19 and
then I got one more place after this.
Pick it up at verse 16. What does that
say?
And it shall come to pass that everyone
that is left of all the nations which
came against Jerusalem shall even go up
from year to year to worship the King,
the Lord of hosts, and to keep the feast
of tabernacles.
>> Oh, remember there's no middle wall
between us now. And those that are left
off of all nations, you got to come up
to Jerusalem to keep the feast of
tabernacle. Remember, there's no middle
wall between us now. So, the Lord We
have access to one spirit which is by
the father which is through Jesus. And
we got to go and worship Jesus. All
nations got to go up to Jerusalem now.
There is no more middle wall between us
now because we are all one. Keep reading
my brother. And it shall be that who
will not come up of all the families of
the earth unto Jerusalem to worship the
king the Lord of hosts even upon them
shall be no rain.
>> Okay. So if when the feast of tab
tabernacles come up and you choose to be
like man I'm go ahead stay home to rule
I'm over here in Portugal
I ain't going to be able to make it up
to you. The Lord ain't going to rain on
you. Why? Because there's no middle wall
between us now. We all worshiping the
same God. So in the future, we all got
to do what this God want us to do.
There's no middle. So if you choose to
stay home during that feast, you ain't
going to get no rain. Go ahead and read.
>> And if the family of Egypt go not up and
come not that have no rain, there shall
be the plague with the Lord will smite
the heathen that come not up to the
feast of tabernacles.
>> Guess what? The B whooping that you
going get, you ain't going to get no
rain. Oh, you thought this Israel was
going to only get the B whooping. No,
you choose not to come up to keep the
feast, you ain't going to get no rain.
And that is your punishment. Go ahead
and read.
>> This shall be the punishment of Egypt
and the punishment of all nations that
come not up to keep the feast of
tabernacles.
>> The Lord have taken down the middle wall
between us. So everybody in this world
has to come up to keep the feast of
tabernacles which is in Jerusalem. Why?
Because that's where the Lord is
reigning over the house of Jacob
forever. Why? Because that is his
habitation. That is where he's going to
dwell forever. Why? Because the
strangers and Israel can pray to and
that's where his eyes at is perpetually.
So since his eyes there perpetually, you
better come up and keep the feast now
because if you don't, you ain't going to
get no rain. And there ain't no need for
me to come visit you over there either
because you ain't getting no rain
either.
>> Just gonna stay my butt in Jerusalem. So
now let's go to our last place. Jeremiah
and we're going to read verse 35 through
37. This is our last
place.
We all got to come up to keep the feast
and to worship the king.
Everybody has to take part of the
commonwealth of Israel. Why? Because the
Lord has not cast off Israel. This is
still going.
Jeremiah 31.
We're going to read verse 35 through
verse 37. We're going to make sure we
understand this before we get up out of
here.
Or if we don't, I can start the lesson
all over and add 17,000 more scriptures
to it.
>> But we're going to make sure we
understand that.
>> It's going to taste good to you. Going
to take real good. Verse 30 35. What
does that say?
>> Thus say the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Which giveth the sun for a light by day.
>> And we see that, right? Go ahead.
>> And the ordinances of the moon and of
the stars for a light by night.
>> Yeah.
>> Which divideth the sea when the waves
thereof roar. The Lord of hosts is his
name.
>> Yes.
>> If those ordinances depart from before
me, said the Lord, then the seed of
Israel also shall cease from being a
nation before me forever.
>> Last verse, verse 37.
>> Thus said the Lord.
>> Uhhuh.
>> If heaven above can be measured,
>> if heaven above can be measured, go
ahead.
>> And the foundations of the earth
searched out beneath.
>> Uhhuh. I will also cast off all the seed
of Israel for all that they have done
say the Lord.
>> All right, pop quiz. Now this open book
test. You can look down and get the
answers. I ain't going to do you like
the teacher.
So can the foundations of the earth be
searched out? No.
Can the heavens above be measured? No.
Does the sun give light by day? Yes.
Does the moon and the stars give light
by night? Yes. Then Israel is not cast
away.
>> Thank you for your time.
Come Down,
Lord.
Come down.
Come down,
Lord.
Come down.